山托斯銀行
- 你有貸款申請書？ - 好極了
- You have a loan app? Wonderful. - Yeah. Terrific.
前幾天我和太太吃晚飯。剛結婚
My wife and l were having dinner the other night-- recently married.
- 我是否能為你效勞？ - 羅莉塔
- How can l help you, sir? - Loretta,
看到沒有， 哪個和經理講話手提箱開著的人
see the man talking to your bank manager has his case open?
那是戈登先生,助理經理之一
Oh, that's Mr. Gwendon, one of our assistant managers.
我們經理是蕭恩先生 但是他今天不在
Our manager is Mr. Schoen, but he's not in today.
-你看到那個帶手提箱的人？ -是
-But you see the man with the briefcase. -Yes.
那是我的同夥，他有槍。
That's my partner. He has a gun in there.
如果你不照我說的做
lf you don't do exactly what l tell you or if you give me any kind of problem at all,
我看一眼我的同夥 他就會朝戈登先生的眉心開槍
I'm going to look at my partner and he's going to shoot your Mr. Gwendon between the eyes.
好
Okay.
行，去拿個大的信封 裝好100, 50, 20鈔票
All right, take one of those big envelopes and put as many 100s, 50s and 20s as you can into it.
不要銀行的袋子和橡皮筋、染色包，和有記號的錢
Nothing with bank straps or rubber bands. I don't want dye packs. I don't want bait money.
從第二個抽屜開始，然後那一個
Start with the second drawer, and then the one over there, under the money counter.
好，快，羅莉塔。鑰匙就在旁邊
Okay. It's okay. Come on, Loretta. Key's right next to you.
對了
There you go.
不要最下邊的
No bills off the bottom of the drawer, please.
這是你第一次被搶？
This your first time being robbed?
你做得蠻好，保持笑容 不要看起來被搶的樣子
You're doing great. Just smile so you don't look like you're being held up.
你笑得很美
You got a very pretty smile.
給我20元的，我要那些
You got 20s? Give me the 20s. l'll take those.
不錯，放到我的口袋裡
There you go. l'll put those in my pocket.
對了
There you go.
我還沒有和我同夥打暗號
l have to give my partner a sign. Now, that's good.
他會等我離開並確定你沒按警鈴
He's gonna wait until I'm out of the building, make sure you haven't set off the alarm.
如果你那麼做，他就會對準戈登先生的眉心開槍
lf you have, he's gonna shoot your Mr. Gwendon between the eyes. Okay?
- 好 - 這樣夠了，羅莉塔
- Okay. - l think that'll do it, Loretta.
謝謝，祝你順利
Thank you. Have a nice day.
你也是
You too.
她很可愛，不是嗎？
Hey-- she's cute, isn't she?
她看起來很甜
Yeah, she seems very nice.
那是誰？
Who was that?
要命，真要命
No, no, no, no, no.
狗娘養的
Son of a bitch!
Fuck! Fuck!
我想你加太多油了 先生，請下車
l think you flooded it. Get out of the car, sir.
- 你要聽個笑話嗎？ - 閉嘴！下車
- Hey, you wanna hear a funny story? - Shut up and get out of the car!
好吧
Yeah. Okay.
格雷茲監獄
貝格雷茲，佛羅里達州
走, 走, 走!
Go, go, go!
那要幹嘛？弗裡
You want somethin', Foley?
有人要逃走，想要知道何時何地嗎？
Some fellas are goin' out of here. What if l tell you where and when?
- 有多少人？ - 我要你把風
- How many? - Expect you to look out for me, let me run off work detail--
好！有多少人出去？
Okay, okay. How many goin' out?
- 聽說六個 - 什麼時候？
- l hear six. - When?
-今晚 -你知道有誰？
- Tonight. - You know who they are?
知道，但我不能告訴你
Yes, l do. But I'm not gonna tell you just yet.
上鎖前在教堂見我
Meet me in the chapel, just before lockdown. Okay?
- 你好 - 我愛你
- You all right? - l love you, baby.
今晚有大事，你興奮嗎？
Tonight's the big night. You excited?
- 是超級杯星期日？ - 你提前了？
- It's Super Bowl Sunday, okay? - See you moved it up.
- 你為何那麼想？ - 今天早上我看你跑步
- Why you think that? - l saw you runnin' this mornin'.
只是例行公事
Stickin' to your routine in case anybody happened to notice.
但你只跑了幾里，不是平常的5里
But you only did a couple of miles, instead of your usual five.
好省點力氣做大事 什麼事？早做完了
Saving yourself for the big event. What happened? Finish ahead of schedule?
你看到那裡的柱子嗎？
Mira, you see those posts out there?
他們要在原來的鐵絲網後15尺的地方再築一道
They're putting up another fence 15 feet back the fence that's already there, you know?
如果在星期日超級杯前鐵絲網已經築好了
So you figure, mira, we wait till Super Bowl Sunday, they have that fence built...
那我們就要在挖個九到十天
then, cono, we gotta dig what, another nine, ten days, baby?
- 是啊 - 我想不會
- Yeah. - I don't think so.
所以今天天黑後我要逃出去 你可以來，弗裡
So tonight, when it gets dark, batta-bing, I'm outta here. Come on, Foley. You could come.
謝謝提議，倒是非常誘人
l appreciate the offer, and it's tempting.
什麼？到邁阿密要100里？
It's a long run to civilization. What's it? A hundred miles to Miami?
我太老了，做不了這種特技
I'm too old to be tryin' a stunt like that.
你出去就寄明信片來
So, you send me a postcard when you get out.
邁阿密
- 我是阿黛爾德麗西 - 你要接受傑克·弗裡打來的由你付款的電話嗎
- Adele Delisi speaking. - Will you accept a collect call from Jack Foley?
我接受
Yeah, l'll accept.
- 阿黛爾，你好 - 嘿，搶銀行的
- Hey, Adele, how you doin'? - Hey, bank robber.
- 要聽忠告嗎？ - 下一次把引擎開著
Want some advice? Next time, keep the engine running.
- 呵呵！好好笑啊 - 你要什麼？傑克
- Huh-huh. That's funny! - What do you want, Jack?
阿黛爾，下星期天超級杯派對……
Adele, you know that Super Bowl party that was for next Sunday?
他們改變了日期，是今晚6：30
They changed the date. It's tonight at 6:30.
- 你說過電話不會被監聽 - 原則上不會
- Didn't you tell me one time calls aren't monitored? - l said, not as a rule.
那就告訴我你在說什麼
So why don't you just come right out and tell me what you're talkin' about?
- 在自由國度的快嘴小姐 - 自由怎麼樣？
- Listen to Miss Smarty Mouth, out there in the free world. - Oh, yeah, what's free about it?
我在找工作
I'm lookin' for work.
- 曼卓魔術師如何？ - 神奇的伊米
- What about Mandrake the Magician? - Emil, The Amazing, huh?
他炒了我魷魚 雇了個年輕的紅髮的女郎
He fired me. Hired a younger girl-- a redhead.
我打電話是因他們改了日期
Adele, the reason I'm calling-- they changed the date.
今晚6:30，還有幾小時
lt is tonight. It's 6:30. That's like a few hours from now.
- 和巴蒂聯絡 - 和在另一車的傢伙
- You tell Buddy-- - Okay, all right, and the guy driving the other car?
- 哪個？ - 因為你老搞不定車子
- What are you talking about? - Well, seeing as you have so much luck with cars,
巴蒂想要帶兩輛車比較穩
Buddy thought it might be better to bring two, you know?
他說找了個你在蘭坡認識的傢伙
He got this guy who says you know him, from Lompoc--
- 葛蘭什麼的 - 葛蘭麥克
- Uh, Glenn somebody-- - Glenn Michaels.
是他，巴蒂說葛蘭認為你們這一夥真酷
Uh-huh, that's him. Buddy said Glenn thinks you guys are real cool.
- 阿黛爾？ - 呀？
- Adele? - Yeah?
告訴巴蒂如果葛蘭戴太陽眼鏡，我就踩爛他
You tell Buddy l see Glenn wearing his sunglasses, I'm gonna step on 'em.
- 我甚至一開始就不拿下來 - 好的，我會的
- Might not even take 'em off first. - Okay, honey. l'll do that.
小心不要被射死，拜拜。
Now, you try not to get shot. Bye.
嗨
Hey--
夫人，我來幫你
Here, ma'am. Let me help you with these.
像你這樣的漂亮女士，不應該搬雜貨
Beautiful young lady like you shouldn't be carrying groceries.
該讓男人來幫你做
Let a man do that for you.
我沒要你幫忙，不要期望小費
Now, l didn't ask for your help, so don't expect a tip.
沒問題，夫人，那我就開走你的車
Oh, that's okay, ma'am. l'll just take your car.
生日快樂
Happy birthday.
又是一套香奈爾的套裝
Did you fit another Chanel suit in here?
有更棒的，打開它
Something much better. Go ahead, open it.
天啊！真漂亮
Oh, my God. It's beautiful.
- 這是…… - 是西格380
- It's a, um-- - Sig Sauer 380.
- 對 - 我真喜歡
- Right. - Oh, l love it!
謝謝，爸
Thanks, Dad.
生日快樂
Happy birthday.
- 再來些咖啡？ - 我不要了
- How 'bout some more coffee? - You know, I can't.
我要去格雷茲 十點跟雷尼可見面
l have to go out to Glades, and then I'm meeting Ray Nicolet at 10:00.
哪個？ 在聯邦火器局那個？
Which one is that? The A.T.F. guy?
他現在聯邦調查局，調過來了
Actually, he's with the F.B.l. now. He switched over.
- 但他已結婚 - 在法律上是，他們已分居
- He's still married, though. - Technically. They're separated.
- 他搬出來了嗎？ - 差不多了
- Well, so he's moved out then. - He's about to.
- 那他們還不算分居 - 能不能不談這些？
- Well, then they're not separated, are they? - Can we not talk about this?
- 你去格雷茲幹什麼？ - 送傳票和控訴狀
- What are you doing at Glades? - Serving process-- a summons and complaint.
有個終身監禁的罪犯不喜歡起司通心粉
Some con doing mandatory life doesn't like macaroni and cheese.
所以他提出控訴說，他不能選擇他們的服務
So, he files suit. Says he doesn't have any choice in what they serve,
這侵犯了他的人權
and that violates his civil rights.
- 你可以到我這裡做我的調查員 - 不，謝了
- You can step in, work full-time as one of my investigators. - No, thanks.
- 你以前喜歡做 - 爸
- You used to like it. - Dad.
你可以和那些律師、醫生約會， 只要他們離了婚
You'd meet doctors, lawyers-- nothing wrong with them, if they're divorced.
凱倫，為什麼把時間那浪費在牛仔警察身上
Karen, why waste your time on some cowboy cop...
他酗酒又不尊重老婆
who drinks too much and cheats on his wife?
他們就是這種人
That's how those hot shots are-- all of 'em!
我真要走了
l really gotta go.
我們不像以前那樣聊得多了
We don't talk much anymore.
我星期天過來，一起看超級杯？
How 'bout l come over Sunday and we watch the Super Bowl together?
太好了
l'd like that.
爸，謝謝那支槍
Thanks for the gun, Dad.
他們在你下面挖了一條地道
They're right underneath you, Pup. They dug a tunnel.
我沒聽說，地道從那裡出來？
I don't hear anything. Where's the tunnel come out?
從守望塔第四根柱子
Fourth post from the guard tower.
我什麼也沒看見
I don't see nothin'.
繼續看
You just keep watchin'.
聯邦調查局，請問找哪位？
Federal Bureau of lnvestigation, how may l direct your call?
我是凱倫西斯柯，找雷尼可
Yeah, this is Karen Sisco again for Ray Nicolet.
請稍等
Hold, please.
好
Yeah.
占線，你要留言嗎？
The line is busy. Would you like his voice mail?
不用了，我等一下再打
No, forget it. l'll call back later.
- 好的 - 謝謝
- All right. - Thanks.
還是沒看到
StilI don't see anything.
你馬上就看到了
You will directly.
等一下
Wait a minute.
尼古丁口香糖
見鬼！
What the fuck?
鐵絲網旁邊有兩個人！
Two men by the fence!
她在搞什麼鬼？
What the hell is she doin'?
別動！舉起手來！
Stop! Get your hands in the air!
地道裡沒人
Tunnel's clear. Seal up the north face.
- 發生什麼事？ - 你說呢？有人越獄了
- What happened? - What the hell do you think, jackass? Got a jail break!
古巴人在哪裡？別對著我 嘿！巴蒂！
Cubans out in the cane. Don't point that thing at me. Hey, Buddy.
- 別緊張，我們是好人 - 你在這裡幹什麼？
- It's okay, we're the good guys. - What are you doing here?
她只是個女孩，為什麼用槍？
All right. You're just a girl. What do you do for a living you pack a shotgun?
- 我是聯邦警察，你被捕了！ - 可能都是
- I'm a federal marshal and you're under arrest. - That's probably all the hacks.
我們等會再說吧
Why don't we talk about this later?
小心你的頭
Watch your head.
我進來了，走吧
I'm in. Let's go!
- 你舒服嗎？ - 太擠了
- Hey! You comfy? - lf l could have a little more room--
沒地方了
Well, there isn't any.
這裡有好東西，手銬啊
We got a lot of shit in here. We got handcuffs in here.
這罐子裡是什麼？
What's in this can?
除口臭的，擠一點到你嘴巴裡
That's for your breath. You could use it-- squirt some in your mouth.
那是美斯，不是嗎？
Yeah, well, that's mace, isn't it?
好吧！你，去……
All right, you! Get--
嘿，你的槍呢？你的手槍
Hey. Where's your gun-- pistol?
在車裡，我的包裡
ln my bag, in the car.
要命，這裡真臭
Boy, it stunk in there.
我想是的，你把我爸給我的值900元的套裝弄壞了
l believe it. You're ruining a $900 suit my dad gave me.
它和那只12口徑的槍很配
Yeah, it went great with that 12-gauge too.
像你這種人怎麼會當法警
Why in the world would someone like you become a federal marshal?
- 專門抓你這種人 - 那是什麼意思？
- The idea of going after guys like you appealed to me. - Sorry, what was that?
像我這種人！讓我告訴你吧
Guys like me? Let me tell you something.
雖然我近來單身，但是我不是非要纏著你不可
Even though l've been celibate lately, I'm not going to force myself on you.
- 我從沒做過 - 你不會有時間做
- l've never done that in my life. - You wouldn't have time, anyway.
碰到路障，他們查車後就會知道這是誰的車了
We come to a roadblock, they run the car and find out who it belongs to.
即使他們要設的話，我懷疑他們能否及時設一個
That's if they get set up in time, which l doubt. lf they do,
他們要找兩個拉丁人，而不是個黑大個.
they'll be lookin' for a bunch of little Latin fellas, not a big black guy drivin' a Ford.
他真是你的好兄弟，如此拿自己來犧牲
He must be quite a pal, to risk his own ass like this.
巴蒂，他是個好傢伙
Buddy? Yeah, he's a good guy.
我們一起坐牢時，他每週一定打電話給他姐姐
Back when we jailed together, he used to call his sister every week, without fail.
她是重生的基督徒，給電視布道家記賬
She's a born-again Christian. She does bookkeeping for a televangelist.
他會打電話向她懺悔
He'd call her up, confess his sins.
告訴他搶過的銀行
He'd tell her whatever bank he happened to rob at the time.
巴蒂是他的名字嗎？
Buddy-- that his given name?
對！我給他取得
The one l gave him, yeah.
你叫什麼？
So, what's your name?
明天看報就知道了
Be in the paper tomorrow, anyway.
傑克弗裡，你恐怕聽過
Jack Foley. You've probably heard of me.
-為什麼，你很有名嗎？ -我在加州被判刑時
-Why? Are you famous? -The time l was convicted in California,
調查局說我搶銀行的紀錄比誰都多
the F.B.l. told me that l'd robbed more banks than anybody in the computer.
- 多少次？ - 我真的不知道
- How many was that? - Tell you the truth, I don't really know.
我18歲時開始替我叔叔卡利和他搭檔開車
Started when l was 18 years old, driving for my Uncle Cully, and his partner, Gus.
你是說你半輩子都在牢裡
So, basically you're saying you spent half your life in prison.
對，如果再被逮住，要關30年
Basically, yeah. l go back, l do 30 years. No time off.
- 你能想像嗎？ - 我不用想，我又不搶銀行
- You imagine lookin' at that? - I don't have to. I don't rob banks.
你好像一點都不怕
You don't seem all that scared.
- 我當然怕 - 看不出來
- Of course l am. - You don't act like it.
你要我大叫嗎？
What do you want me to do, scream?
那也起不了作用
That wouldn't help much, anyway.
我打算坐在這裡，等你自己搞砸
No, I'm just gonna sit here, take it easy, and wait for you to screw up.
聽起來像我前妻
You sound like my ex-wife.
- 你結過婚 - 一年左右
- You were married? - Just for about a year, give or take a few days.
我們相處得不錯，只是……
It's not like we didn't get along-- we had fun. We just...
沒有那種……
didn't have... that thing, you know, that uh--
- 激情，那很重要 - 嗯哼
- That spark, you know? Gotta have that. - Mm-hmm.
- 儘管我們仍在說話 - 是嗎？
- We still talk, though. - Sure.
你是不會有好下場的 做這種事永遠都不會有
This is not gonna end well. These things never do.
我要死也想被人打死在大街上
lf it turns out l get shot like a dog, it's gonna be in the street,
不想死在牢裡
not off a goddamn fence.
你真以為你是什麼克萊貝羅
You must really see yourself as some kind of Clyde Barrow, huh?
- 你是指邦尼和克萊 - 是的
- You mean, of Bonnie and Clyde? - Yeah.
電影中他們中彈 華倫比提和……
The part in the movie where they get shot, when it's Warren Beatty and--
- 費唐 娜薇 - 費唐 娜薇，yeah.
- Faye Dunaway. - Faye Dunaway, yeah.
- 我喜歡她演的「電視網」 - 演得真好
- l like her in that movie about TV. - Network, yeah, she was good.
那傢伙說他再不吃那套
And that guy says he's not gonna take any more shit from anybody.
- 彼特 芬奇 - Yeah! 彼特 芬奇
- Peter Finch. - Yeah! Peter Finch.
「我已經火大了，我不會吃你那套」
''I'm mad as hell, and I'm not gonna take any more of your shit!''
在他們中槍的那一節，我記得我一直在想……
ln that part where they get shot, l can remember thinkin' to myself,
如果你別無選擇的時候，這個結局也不算太壞
thinkin', ''Hey, that wouldn't be such a bad way to go, if you had to.''
你很會和人聊天
You sure are easy to talk to.
如果我們在不同的場合下遇到
l was thinkin', if we met under different circumstances--
你在酒吧，我出現，我們交談
if you were in a bar and l came up and we started talkin'--
- 然後呢？ - 沒有了
- l wonder what would happen. - Nothing.
- 如果你不知道我是誰 - 你可能會告訴我
- lf you didn't know who l was. - You'd probably tell me.
- 如果場合不同…… - 你在開玩笑
- Just saying if we met under different circumstances-- - You have got to be kidding.
是, 是
Yeah. Yeah.
我喜歡另一部費唐娜薇演的電影是《三日兀鷹》
Another movie l liked with Faye Dunaway was Three Days of the Condor.
勞伯瑞夫年輕時拍的那部
The one with Robert Redford when he was young.
是
Yeah.
那部電影一點意思都沒有
You know, l never thought it made sense, though--
他們那麼快就好上了
you know, the way they got together so quick.
是嘛？
Why not?
- 很浪漫 - 嗯哼
- l mean, romantically. - Mm-hmm.
可是……
Well, but it-- if-- uh. All right.
又停了。 我們現在在哪裡?
Here we go. All right. Where the hell are we?
公路收費口，葛蘭在上面另一輛車裡
At the turnpike. Glenn's right above us with the other car.
- 快出來! - 背過身舉起手
- All right, c'mon. Hop on out. - Turn around and get your hands up!
快出來!背過身舉起手
Shit!
別管她，反正我們也不要這輛車了
We may as well leave her. We're leavin' the car...
我們總要把她甩了
and we gotta leave her someplace, anyway-- what's the difference where?
- 她得跟著我們。 - 天啊，你在那裡搞什麼?
- She's comin' with us. - Jesus Christ, what were you doing in there?
- 找名字 - 找過了
- Look for a name. - l already looked.
她叫凱倫西思科，像席司科孩童，拼法不同
Her name is Karen Sisco. Like the Cisco Kid, only spelled different.
S-l-S-C-O.
Karen?
凱倫，你要老實一點
All right, Karen? You be a good girl, now.
我要打開後車蓋了
I'm gonna open up the trunk.
喂! 喂! 喂! 你在往自己車上打窟窿
Hey, hey, hey, now! Now, you're puttin' holes in your car!
我不會把你扔在這裡， 我要開後車蓋，你把槍扔出來。
I'm not leavin' you. I'm gonna open the trunk enough for you to drop your pistol out.
巴蒂有你的獵槍， 你要開槍的話，他會射回去
Now, if you shoot, Buddy's got your shotgun, he's gonna shoot back.
我攔不住他，就看你自己了
There's nothin' l can do about it, so it's up to you.
別開槍!是葛蘭
Hey. Don't! It's Glenn! Whoa!
媽的，傑克，很高興見到你
Fuck! Hey, hey, Jack. Good to see you, man.
你們在射誰?
What the fuck are you guys shooting at?
- 我們要他嗎? - 警察見過這輛車
- Do we need 'im? - The cop saw this car.
- 他可能會起疑心再調回頭 - 好吧
- He might tie it to the break and turn around. - All right.
- 嘿，小伙子，我們沒認出你 - 嘿，「小伙子。」
- Hey, Studs. We didn't recognize ya. - Hey, ''Studs,'' man.
從蘭坡出來後就沒有聽過混得怎麼樣?
l haven't heard that since Lompoc, man. So what's goin' on?
沒怎麼樣
Aw, nothin'.
凱倫，你要出來嗎?
Karen. Are you comin' out?
- 聽到了嗎？ - 好吧。
- You hear that? - Okay!
—聽到了嗎？好吧。
Okay.
算你贏，傑克
You win, Jack.
衣服乾洗完後 帳單寄給我
Now, you get your clothes cleaned, you send me the bill.
我會寄到葛雷茲去
l'll send it to you at Glades.
你是不是剛從陰溝洞裡爬出來?你是誰?
What, did you crawl through a sewer, man? Who're you?
- 摘下墨鏡 - 戴著看得更清楚
- Take your sunglasses off. - l see better with 'em on, man.
小心我把你和墨鏡一起扔到天橋上去
You don't take 'em off I'm gonna throw them off while they're still on your head.
- 等在車裡 - 文明社會裡，說話客氣點
- Go wait in the car. - Um, we're in civilization now, so you can ease up a little bit.
對不起，請你在車裡等，帶上她，放在後座!
I'm sorry. l'd like you to wait in the car, please. Take her, put her in the back.
- 後車廂？後坐！
- Okay. ln the trunk? - ln the backseat! ln the backseat!
- 過來!因為我要…… - 把外套給我!
- Backseat. Okay, you gotta come now, 'cause l gotta do this-- - Gimme your jacket.
我需要乾淨衣服
Somebody forgot to bring the clean clothes.
乾淨衣服在凱迪拉克車裡
l brought 'em. They're at Glades in the back of the Cadillac.
是你自己要跳進她的後車箱
You decided to jump into the trunk of her car.
你可以怪我，我不介意
You can blame me if you want. I don't mind.
—給你：我要告訴你……
- Here, sir. - l'll tell you--
- 你有什麼毛病? - 你為什麼叫葛蘭來
- What's your problem, Jack? - I don't know why you got Glenn involved in this.
- 這件事是他的主意 - 他?
- How 'bout the score was his idea to begin with? - ldea--
他沒有大腦的
The guy's got a fuckin' vacant lot for a head.
他以為他可以用這種口氣跟我說話
He thinks he can talk to me like that? Shit.
「把外套給我」我坐在這裡等了半個鐘頭
''Gimme your jacket.'' l have been sitting here for over a half-hour,
防備著警察。你以為那是好玩的?
watchin' out for the Highway Patrol, if you think that's fun.
我得鑽進灌木叢……
God. You know, l hadda go over there in the bushes...
抽根大麻，這樣我才能…你知道嗎?
to smoke a joint, just so l could like-- you know?
對。我在北部有大計劃
Yep. l got somethin' big lined up, up north.
如果沒有我，這些傢伙怎麼可能知道
Yeah, these guys? Wouldn't even fuckin' know about it if it wasn't for me.
- 他一講話我就想揍他 - 他不是問題。
- Every time he opens his mouth, l wanna punch him out. - He's not the problem, Jack.
你幹什麼要把她帶著?
You wanna pull your head outta your ass, tell me why the hell we're bringing her with us?
葛蘭
Glenn.
你不記得我了嗎?
You don't remember me, do you?
我從未進過葛雷茲，如果你是這個意思的話
Um, couldn't have been Glades if that's what you're thinkin', 'cause l was never out there.
- 我不是這個意思 - 是
- No, that's not what I'm thinking. - Oh, yeah?
但你肯定我們見過?
But you're sure we've met, huh?
去年秋天
Last fall.
我押著你從棕櫚灘縣監獄到聯邦法院，兩次。
l drove you from the Palm Beach County Jail to the federal courthouse... twice.
你是葛蘭麥克
You're Glenn Michaels.
我從不忘記我逮過的任何人
l never forget anybody l've cuffed and shackled.
讓我們來想想辦法，葛蘭
Now let's think about this for a minute, Glenn, see if we can't work it out.
車裡有槍嗎？
Do we have a gun in the car?
見鬼，我記起來了
Oh, shit! l remember you! Hey!
弗理不會有好下場的，他完蛋，你也跟著完蛋
Foley's not gonna make it, and if he goes down, you go with him.
- 你們關係近的話我倒能瞭解。 - 不，我跟他根本不熟
- Now, look. l can understand if you guys are close, but-- - No, we're not.
- 但我現在是在幫他 - 等一下，葛蘭。
- But, yeah. I'm helpin' him. - Now wait a minute, Glenn.
你以前幫過他嗎?
Have you helped him?
目前我想你還應該不會被控「越獄共犯」的罪名
l mean, technically, at this point, l doubt you could be charged with aiding a fugitive.
你還有機會
So you still have a choice.
你想把她帶到我那裡洗乾淨，抹上科龍水……
You wanna take her to my place, get cleaned up, come out of the bathroom...
出來，然後她說「原來我看錯你了。」
with your aftershave on, and she goes, ''Oh. l had you all wrong.''
我只是想同她再聊幾句
No. l just wanna talk to her again, that's all.
看看在正常情況下會怎樣
l just wanna see what it might have been like under normal circumstances.
太遲了
It's too late for that, Jack.
他想擺脫我們，我不怪他
He wants to get out of here, and I don't blame him.
兩年前
在蘭坡聯邦監獄
如果裁判再不叫停的話，那小子要被裝在裹屍袋抬出去了。
Ref don't call it soon, Snoop's gonna send this cat out in a body bag.
你知道他們為什麼叫他「史努比?」
Anybody ever tell you why they call him ''Snoopy''?
他以前叫「瘋狗」莫瑞
He used to be Maurice ''Mad Dog'' Miller...
當他還是職業拳手的時候
back when he was a pro.
現在你輕拍他，他就倒下來
Now you pet him, he goes down.
- 難以置信 - 天啊!
- I don't believe it! - Oh, my!
胡鬧!胡鬧
Bullshit! Bullshit!
好，你行
Yeah, you the man.
那小子到處吹他
Guy's bragging he won a thrown fight.
贏了一場做假的拳賽
Fuckin' pathetic.
他要倒楣了
Dangerous is what it is.
- 那個禿子是誰?  - 理查瑞利。
- Who's the bald dude? - Richard Ripley.
華爾街的?
The Wall Street guy?
他騙了好多人的錢，渾號騙子迪克
Call him Dick The Ripper on account of all the guys he ripped off.
沒戴假髮我都認不出他
Oh, yeah. l didn't recognize him without his rug.
- 他被判多少年?  - 三年。
- What's his bid? - Three years.
你們被罰了嗎?
You guys on the bench? Okay.
三年，罰金五千萬，他媽的就寫了張支票
Three years, fined $50 million and wrote 'em a fuckin' check.
就這樣
Just like that.
五千萬，簽一個名而已
Fifty mill, signed his name.
還沒有…對了…幫個小忙
Didn't even-- Didn't even-- Okay, a little help.
夠了，太重
Okay, heavy!
天!太重了
Heavy! Come on!
陽光刺眼，看不清上面的數字。
All the bright glare out here, you couldn't read the numbers on the weights.
我知道了
Oh. l had it. Jesus.
- 你怎麼知道他寫了張支票？ - 他告訴我的。
- How do you know he wrote a check? - Uh, he told me.
我們一起在洗衣房當差
We work laundry together.
那傢伙真他媽的愛說。
Guy loves to fucking talk.
他愛說：他告訴聯邦檢察官
Yeah, he loves to talk. He talked to the U.S. attorney.
他被那些與他做生意的人告發了
Rolled over on all the snitches he was doing business with.
有哪個傢伙能拿出五千萬的支票
Hey! Any guy who can write a fuckin' check for $50 million,
他說什麼我都聽
he says anything, I'm all fuckin' ears.
他告訴我他把錢都存在外國銀行
Guy tells me he's got all this money in foreign banks.
加上，大概……
Plus, around, mmm,
他家裡值五百萬未加工的鑽石
five million in uncut diamonds at his house.
他說
He said, quote,
「我可以隨時動這筆錢。」
that l can get my hands on it at any time.
- 他住哪裡？ - 底特律。
- Where does he live? - Detroit.
史努比米勒說未加工的鑽石跟現金一樣好處理。
Snoopy Miller says that uncut diamonds are as easy to move as cash.
見過未加工的鑽石嗎?
Ever seen an uncut diamond, Studs?
就像一般石頭
Looks just like a plain, old rock.
慢著，你以為他在說謊?
Wait, you think this guy's lying?
你說呢?用你的大腦想一想如果他有五百萬，
What do you think, Studs? Use your head. Some guy's got $5 million...
他會告訴你這樣在監獄裡的大嘴巴?
socked away in his house, and he's gonna tell some motormouth he just met in prison about it.
我就知道你們不會相信我
Oh, l see. You guys are cynical. Right.
來了
Here it comes.
別停下，繼續走
Keep on walking. Keep walking.
你別回答任何問題
You don't wanna be answering any questions.
我只是說她一點都不怕
I'm just saying she wasn't scared, that's all.
因為她手裡有手槍
That's 'cause she had her hand on her gun the whole time waitin' to make her move.
你是嫉妒你沒有在後車箱跟她在一起。。。
You're just jealous 'cause it was me in the trunk with her...
- 不是你 - 對了。
- and not you. - You're right.
讓我先把自己弄乾淨
The first thing I'm gonna do... is get this mud off me.
喂。
Hey.
凱倫
Karen?
凱倫，親愛的?
Karen, honey?
凱倫
Karen?
你說夢話
You were talking in your sleep.
我說了甚麼
What'd l say?
「嘿，你自己。」
''Hey, yourself.''
喂
Huh.
喂，丹尼爾
Hello, Daniel.
丹尼爾波頓，聯邦調查局
Daniel Burdon, F.B.l.
聯邦警察西思柯，凱倫的父親。
Marshall Sisco, Karen's dad.
- Hmm. - Hmm.
Umm--
請你在外面等等
Would you mind, please, waiting outside?
我們有事要談
We have some business to do here.
反正我要上廁所
Well, uh, l have to use the john anyway.
對不起。
- Excuse me. - Yeah.
我要加入特勤小組 丹尼爾
l wanna be on the task force, Daniel.
嗯--
Well--
謝謝你的好意，但是……
That's nice of you to offer, Karen, but...
我已有足夠的人力
l got all the help l can use right now.
讓我們談一下你頭上的包是怎麼來的
lnstead, let's talk about how you got that bump on your head.
你手上拿的不是我的卷宗嗎?
lsn't that my file you're holding on to?
是的，但是我要聽你親口講
Yes, but l want to hear it from you,
從你和他搶駕駛盤開始
starting... with when you grabbed the wheel.
這是在那兒?
Where was this?
快到歐基喬比出口的地方
Coming to the Okeechobee exit.
- 坐好! - 你戴著墨鏡，能看得到嗎?
- Sit back! - Can you see with those glasses on?
我很好!這…真笨
I'm fine! This is... stupid, man.
這些傢伙會對我很失望
These guys are gonna be so disappointed in me, man.
你知道嗎？如果不是吸了大麻
You know what? lf l wasn't stoned,
我才不會聽你的
there is no way that you would have talked me into this.
- 記住 - 過了橋就從這裡出去
- Remember that. - Get off at the exit right after that bridge.
我不會去自首
No, l am not fucking turning myself in, so forget it!
- 往那邊開 - 哪邊?
- Get off at that exit! - What exit?
- 那邊的出口 - 坐好!
-That exit right there. Take that exit! -Sit back! No!
當我清醒時
The next thing l knew,
救護人員把我從車裡拖出來
the paramedics were pulling me out of the car.
- 你還好 - 有幾個問題我懷疑的是……
- You all right? - There's a couple of points l keep wondering about--
有關那兩個捉你的傢伙
have to do with the two guys that grabbed you.
是巴蒂?和這個傢伙傑克弗理
Buddy, is it? And this fella Jack Foley.
這個人起碼已搶了200家銀行
l swear, the man must have robbed over 200 banks in his time.
啊？
- Really? - Um-hmm.
他告訴我他記不得搶了多少家
He told me he didn't remember how many he robbed.
那你和他談過話
Then you talked to him.
在後車箱裡，是啊
ln the trunk, yeah.
你們談甚麼?
What'd you talk about?
各種事
Different things.
監獄，電影
Prison, movies.
這傢伙綁架你，你還跟他談電影?
This fella holds you hostage, you talk about movies?
這是個不平凡的經驗
lt was an unusual experience.
弗理讓我想起卡爾提門
You know, Foley made me think of that fella Carl Tillman.
你去看時，他剛巧在搶銀行
The one that you were seeing, it turns out, the same time he was robbing banks.
- 你記不記得? - 卡爾怎麼了?
- Do you recall that? - And what happened to Carl?
你對他開槍。但是你沒打弗理和他的朋友
The time came, you shot him. But you didn't shoot Foley or the guy with him.
他們沒帶武器。你有散彈鎗。卻讓他們把你丟進後車箱。
They're unarmed, you had a shotgun and you let them throw you in the trunk.
你手上有西格手槍
Okay. Now you got your Sig in your hand,
你在報告中說你不能回頭
and you say in the report that you couldn't turn around.
但是當車箱打開時
He had you pinned down. But when the trunk opened,
為什麼你不打死他們?
how come you didn't cap the two guys then?
你平常做什麼？ 捉做手腳的簿記人員?
What do you work on most of the time? Fraud? Go after crooked bookkeepers?
我在局裡十五年，參加過各種不同的調查
Karen, l've been with the bureau 15 years on all kinds of investigations.
- 曾經射殺過人沒有？ - 沒有。
- Have you ever shot a man? - No.
- 你有沒有帶頭破門而入過? - 我還要資格審查?
- When was the last time you were primary through the door? - l have to qualify?
你必須知道你自己在說什麼
You have to know what you're talking about.
下次再談
We'll talk another time. All right, Karen?
奇怪!為什麼弗理在不須要你的時候 還把你放進第二輛車……
l'd like to know why Foley put you in that second car when he didn't need you anymore.
那你只有去問他自己了
You'll have to ask him that.
Rip, Rip.
- 談個交易怎麼樣? - 嗨，莫瑞。
- What the deal is, baby? - Hi, Maurice.
- 我不知道 - 來敲敲手
- Oops. I don't know. - Make a fist--
- 又來了 - 走開
- There you go. - Fuck it, man.
- 我拿到你要的金魚了 - 好
- Got your little fishies for you. - Oh, good.
慢點。價錢漲了
Not so fast. Starting out, there's gonna be an across the board cost of living increase.
- 什麼？ - 我是因信用欺詐被抓進來的
- What? - When l got put in here a year ago on credit card fraud,
不過只是個小角色
l didn't really get no props for that.
但自從我在院子裡捅了那個大嘴巴後
But ever since l shanked that loudmouth pussy in the yard,
我的名聲大漲
it's like my Dun and Broadstreet around this bitch done shot way the fuck up.
變成大英雄了
Actually, it's Dun and Bradstreet. That's the, uh--
我都聽說了
Well, l've heard it both ways.
最重要的是，價錢漲了
Point is that the price has gone up around this bitch too.
把你的黑冊子拿出來我們要辦正事
Get your little black book out. We got some business to talk about.
這些魚，我以前講的價錢是
For the little fishies-- What'd l say they was gonna be?
- 兩千 - 現在是三千
- Two thousand. - Now they're gonna be three thousand.
- 什麼… - 現在是三千
- Come on. You-- - Now they're gonna be three thousand.
那些滴在你眼睛裡的狗屎鹽水
That saltwater shit you put in your eyes?
- 你叫它們什麼? - 眼藥水
- What do you call that? - Bausch & Lomb.
那些狗屎眼藥水，是三百塊
Yeah, that bushy lawn shit. That's 300.
- 我要 - 對，你要。另外那個枕頭
- l need it. - Yeah, you do. And that extra pillow.
我會幫你搞到，但要五百塊
I'm gonna get that for you, but that's gonna be like five C's.
五百?
- Five? - Hey.
標誌上說禁止講話，你們不識字嗎?
Sign says shut the fuck up, or can't you fellas read?
你他媽的和誰講話?
Who the fuck you talkin' to, man?
弗理，你有什麼問題嗎?
You got a problem over there, Foley?
這是我看過最笨的一個敲詐
Yeah, this is the dumbest fucking shakedown in the history of dumb shakedowns.
- 五百塊一個枕頭 - 對啊
- Five hundred bucks for a pillow? - That's right.
- 是有點太貴了 - 閉嘴，迪克
- lt does seem a little high, doesn't it? - Shut up, Dick.
- 一定是好枕頭 - 高級鵝毛的
- Must be a nice pillow. - Full goose down.
- 但是… - 你們一夥賺多少?
- Look, you still-- - How much for your company at chow?
我們一夥?我得看著這狗娘養的
My company? Come on, man. You know l'll watch this motherfucker's back.
- 多少? - 100塊。
- How much? - That's a C-note.
瑞利，叫這傢伙滾開
lf you're smart, Ripley, you'll tell this guy to fuck off.
真的？
Really?
我不知道
Well, l-- l-- I don't know.
他殺了你，什麼也得不到
First of all, if he kills you, then he's gonna get nothin'.
不必殺他，弗理
Well, uh, the man don't just have to die, Foley.
他可能跌倒在硬東西上傷到自己
He could accidentally hurt himself falling down on something real hard.
像刀或我的老二甚麼的
Like a shiv or my dick.
我付錢。我付錢。別擔心
l'll pay. l'll pay it. Don't worry.
如果他跌倒，史努比
lf he falls on anything, Snoop,
他會很快被轉監。快到你想不到
then they're gonna transfer his ass outta here faster than you can throw a fight...
你還是甚麼也得不到
and you're still gonna get nothin'.
上次我查過
You know, last time l checked, man,
這與你無關
this shit over here ain't got nothin' to do with you.
出去抽根煙或甚麼的
Why don't you go outside? Smoke a cigarette or some shit.
我不抽煙
I don't smoke.
你聽到他啦。快滾吧
You heard the man. Why don't you get your punk ass up outta here?
你慘了，那是海米
- Uh-oh. - You fucked up now, man. That's Himey.
我的保鏢，這監獄的第32號狠人物
Protege of mine. Ranked number 32 in the federal prison system.
- 32？ - 對
- Thirty-two? - That's right.
- 在多少，20個人裡面? - 扁他。
- Out of, what, 20. - Kick this cracker's ass.
- 這裡發生了甚麼事? - 沒事。
- What's going on here? - Uh, nothin'.
在看「如何讀書」甚麼的結果大家都興奮起來了。
Just ''reading is fundamental'' shit. We got all excited and everything.
全出去。現在
Clear outta here. Now.
- 沒問題 - 全都走
- No problem. - All of you. Let's go.
我想買魚的事定了 史努比
Uh, Snoopy. l think we settled the fish thing.
這魚。喔!對不起……
Oh, the fish. Yeah.
這是我們握手的方法，老弟
That's how you do the shake, partner.
報上說你們各懸賞一萬。 —奇諾和陸露。
Paper says there's ten grand each on you, Chino and Lulu.
他們有沒有提到凱倫
They say anything about Karen?
只說她跑了
Just that she got away. Here.
傑克
- Hmm? - Jack!
沒關係
- Hey! - That's all right. It's in the pool.
有沒有說她和葛蘭走了以後怎樣?
Did it say what happened to her after she took off with Glenn?
你得問葛蘭
I don't know. You'll have to ask Glenn.
他可能正在去底特律的路上。我們也該去
He's probably on his way to Detroit, which is where we should be.
你知道你在幹麼嗎?
- Yeah. - Do you realize what you're doing?
這女人是執法人員
Worrying about a woman who works for law enforcement?
你想和對你開槍的女人喝雞尾酒?
You wanna sit down and have cocktails with a woman who tried to shoot you.
- 你在聽嗎? - 你想這老傢伙是她男朋友?
- Do you hear what I'm saying? - Do you think this old guy's her boyfriend?
只有這張相片
It's the only picture she has in here.
我一個人去底特律?
Am l going to Detroit by myself?
待在這兒越久，就越可能……
The longer we stay here, the better chance there is...
葛蘭可能搞砸
that either Glenn is gonna screw up the score,
也可能我們被捕，或兩個都是
or we gonna get busted or both.
這是弗理?
This is Foley?
凱倫?
- Karen? - Hmm?
- 這是弗理?
- This is Foley? - How lucky can one guy be
一點也不像……
Doesn't even look like that.
- 不像? - 他看起來比較像……
- Oh, no? - Uh-uh. He looks a lot like--
不一樣
Different.
懷特爾普來了
Wyatt Earp is here.
- 嗨 - 嗨
- Hey. - Hey.
- 感覺怎樣?好一點了嗎?  - 還好。
- How you feelin'? Feel better? - Good. Yeah.
- 你父親照顧你?  - 他請假一禮拜…
- ls your dad taking good care of you? - He took the week off...
想照顧我，但他卻只在修他的船。
to take care of me and he's worked on his boat every day since.
- 這是雷尼可 - 嗨
- Dad, this is Ray Nicolet. - Hi.
- 我聽了好多關於你的事 - 彼此彼此
- Pleasure to meet you. l heard a lot about you. - Likewise.
雷正與調查局特勤小組一同調查越獄案
Ray's working with the F.B.l. task force on the prison break.
告訴我，雷，你有沒有穿過「便衣」字樣的衣服?
l see that. Tell me, Ray, do you ever wear one that says ''undercover''?
- 沒有 - 事情進展如何?
- No. - How's it going?
坐下來
Sit down.
不錯。我們捉到其中一個
Okay. Good. We caught one of them.
- 是弗理嗎? - 從線民的線索來的
- Was it Foley? - Was it off a tip?
有人在機場附近看到他們倆個
Somebody spotted two of them out in this hobo camp near the airport.
打了報案電話
Called in the number. That was it.
- 是懸賞起了作用 - 是弗理嗎?
- l knew it as soon as l as there was a reward. - Was it Foley?
不是，是裡納茲，古巴幫中的一個
No, Linares, one of the Cubans.
我們與霹靂小組，兩架直升機一起攻進去，
We went in there with full SWAT, two choppers, that whole deal.
裡納茲開始開槍，所以我們先逮他
Linares goes nuts, starts shooting, so we took him out.
奇諾溜了
I don't know how Chirino got away, but he did.
- 弗理不在現場 - 只有古巴人而已
- And Foley hadn't been there. - No, this place was strictly Cuban.
弗理搭了車，他一定另有計劃
Foley had a ride. He must have his own agenda. You know what l mean?
他好像是唯一知道自己在幹什麼的人
He seems to be the only guy who kinda knows what he's doing.
Uh-huh.
對不起
- Excuse me. - Yeah.
喂？
Hello?
她在，請等一下
Yeah, she is. Just a minute, please.
凱倫
Karen.
- 喂？ - 嗨!
- Hello? - Hi.
你知道我是誰嗎?
You know who this is?
知道。五分鐘
Yes. Five minutes.
那麼，雷
So. Ray.
有些事我感到奇怪
- Yeah. - There's something I'm wondering.
報紙標題說有個邁阿密女人說她同殺人犯睡覺
The headline reads, ''l slept with a murderer, says shaken Miami woman.''
- 誰接的電話 - 與你無關
- Who is it that answered the phone? - None of your business.
可能對你來說我還不夠成熟
I'm just worried maybe I'm not old enough for you.
- 那是我父親 - 真的?
- lt was my dad. - Really?
- 他一臉警察相 - 你怎麼會知道?
- He's got a cop's face. - How do you know?
- 你拿了我的皮夾 - 還有你的槍
- Oh, wait. You have my wallet. - And your gun.
- 我可以拿回來嗎?  - 要怎麼做?
- Think l can have 'em back? - How do we do that?
來我父親家，丟在他那裡
You can come by my dad's place and drop 'em off.
我乾脆給應門的霹靂小組特警算了
l could leave it with the SWAT guy that answers the door.
現在有個特勤小組的傢伙在這裡
There's a guy here on the task force right now.
也許我該讓他講
Maybe l should put him on the phone and let the two of you work it out.
- 你不會這樣做 - 為什麼不？
- You wouldn't do that. - Why not?
你玩得很愉快嘛
Because you're having too much fun.
她替他煮了豬排飯
She fixes him pork chops and rice.
接著，他們就在沙發上做愛
The next thing you know, they're making love on the sofa.
她說他很溫柔
She says he was very gentle.
奇裡諾來了，說他想他的小女人
This guy, Chirino, shows up at the house, says he misses his little girl.
她覺得對不起他。接著…砰
She feels sorry for him. Next thing you know-- boom.
- 在沙發上 - 這就是你們目前的進展?
- On the couch. - That's how you score now, huh?
是吧
l guess.
我一直在想些事
There's something l've been wondering.
你的卡利叔呢?
Whatever happened to your Uncle Cully?
希望他告訴你我在哪?
You think he's gonna tell you where l am?
- 除非你要 - 他死了
- Unless you wanna tell me. - He's dead.
坐了27年車
Did 27 years before he got out,
出獄幾年後，死在慈善醫院
and he died a couple of years afterwards in a charity hospital...
彌補所有他錯過的好時光
by trying to make up for all the good times he missed.
我絕不會那麼做
That's not gonna be me.
最後一搏，退休到某小島?是嘛?
What, one last score, retire to some island? ls that the idea?
- 傑克 - 我本身偏愛山區
- Jack. - I'm partial to mountains myself,
不過你喜歡小島，我們就去小島
but if you like islands, we'll make it an island.
- 「我們」是指? - 我和你可以…
- What do you mean, ''we'll make it an island''? - You and l can make it--
- 你最好來看看 - 那是巴蒂嗎?
- Jack, you better come and check this out. - ls that Buddy?
- 什麼?好 - 拜拜
- What? No. Okay. Bye-bye. - Who're you talking to?
- 所以，她已婚了 - 正確
- So she's a married woman. - Right.
她和逃犯上床，因為……
But she goes to bed with a prison escapee because...
他說他想念他的小女人
he tells her that he misses his little girl.
她告訴全世界的人，但你卻保護她
She tells the world about it. But you protect her.
你沒洩漏她的姓名
You don't reveal her name.
聽起來她做得不錯
That makes it sound like what she was doing was okay...
只要她老公沒發現
as long as her husband doesn't find out.
就像偷腥的傢伙說老婆不知情就不受傷
Like the guy who cheats on his wife, saying what she doesn't know won't bother her.
- 爸  - 幹嘛？
- Dad. - What?
雷，讓你看個東西。在客廳裡。
Ray, l wanna show you something... in the living room.
很高興跟你聊天
- Yeah. - Good talking to you, Ray.
我也是
Yeah, you too.
今天早上，聯邦警察臨檢一個在邁阿密
Federal law enforcement agents raided a squatters' camp...
國際機場北邊的流浪漢聚所
north of Miami lnternational Airport this morning...
搜尋週二從葛雷茲監獄脫逃的逃犯
in the hopes of capturing a fugitive from Tuesday's daring escape from Glades prison.
其中一名，奧裡李納茲
F.B.l. officials confirm that one of the escapees, Arelio Linares,
- 被殺死 - 奇諾會找我。
- was killed-- - Chino's gonna wanna talk to me.
奇諾忙著逃命，根本不甩你
Chino's runnin' for his life. He don't give a shit about you.
他會知道我放棄他了。他會要找我
He's gonna know by now l gave him up back at Glades. He's gonna wanna find me.
也許問阿黛兒。看她知道什麼?
Maybe see Adele, see what she knows.
他知道她住哪?
He knows where she lives?
傑克！
Jack!
我們曾一起聊天喝過酒
We were talking once, drinking rum,
我可能提過她
and l may have mentioned Adele.
她曾替魔術師工作過。他很感興趣
How she worked for a magician. Chino got all interested.
他說，「你怎麼把女人鋸成兩半？」
He said, ''How do you saw the woman in half?''
當她來探監時，他想見見她
Maybe he wanted to meet her, maybe see her if she came to visit.
所以你打了電話。要她不要跟古巴幫講話
Oh, okay, okay. So you call her up and tell her don't talk to any Cubans.
- 電話可能被監聽了  - 沒錯
- The phone's probably tapped by now. - You're right.
就是說她被監視了
And if the phone is tapped, you know they have her place staked out.
該死
Shit!
阿黛兒 德利西
Adele Delisi speaking.
- 是阿黛兒嗎? - 是啊!
- Uh, uh, this is Adele? - Yes, it is.
抱歉 打錯了
Oh-- Uh, sorry. Wrong number.
喬裝得不錯
Nice disguise.
我是個觀光客
I'm a tourist.
你看
All right. Here we go.
前面這裡左手邊
Coming up right here... on the left.
- 那個剪樹叢的傢伙? - 我想聯邦調查局…
- What about the guy with the clippers? - l wonder what the F.B.l...
剪樹叢要收多少錢?
is charging to trim hedges these days?
- 棋下得有模有樣 - 靠邊停
- Quite a checker game they got goin' on too. - Pull on up.
噢!天啊
Oh, man.
你看得到卻得不到
Okay, you saw her. That's all you get.
- 我們去底特律吧 - 你總算說了句人話
- Let's go to Detroit. - Now you're talkin', brother.
我得替傑克說句話，他很體貼
l'll say one thing for Jack-- he's very considerate.
嗯，時好時壞的
Lights on or off, if you know what l mean.
是啊
- Really. - Hmm.
阿黛兒，聽著
Adele, listen--
我只是想在事情搞得更糟前找到他
l just want to find him before he does something else and makes it worse on himself.
巴蒂會照顧他
No. Buddy'll take care of him.
不讓他惹麻煩。他是傑克的良知
Keep him out of trouble. He's Jack's conscience, always has been.
他們大概一起搶過50家銀行
They must have robbed 50 banks together.
- 是最佳拍檔 - 直到他們被抓
- They were a really great team. - Until they got busted.
那不是傑克的錯，那是因為……
Hmm. That wasn't Jack's fault. No, that was on account of...
巴蒂。他決定在他們行動之前
Buddy, for some reason, decided to call his sister and confess to the job...
向他姊姊坦白
before they'd done it instead of after.
她打給聯邦調查局。結果兩個都進了蘭坡
Well, she called the F.B.l. They both went down, and they ended up at Lompoc.
我想巴蒂有點愧疚
l think Buddy felt kind of bad about that.
阿黛兒，你知道在哪兒可找到巴蒂?
Adele, do you have any idea where l could find Buddy?
或葛蘭?
Or Glenn?
米拉，阿黛兒，在嗎?
Mira, Adele, you in there?
-在  -米拉，我想和你談談
-Yes. -Mira, l'd like to speak to you, please.
- 你是誰? - 伊米。你以前的老闆
- Well, who is it? - Emile, you know, the guy you used to work for?
給我你的電話和地址
- Uh-- - He gave me your number and where you live.
米拉 我在找助理。我能和你談談嗎?
Mira, I'm looking for an assistant. Can l speak to you, please?
好
- Oh. Uh, yeah. - All right.
你替伊米工作過?
You did work for Emile, right?
我當過伊米四年的盒裝美人
Uh, yeah, l was Emile's box jumper for four years, almost.
你是什麼?他的盒子?
Cono! You were what, his box?
他的助理
- Uh, his assistant. - Oh, okay.
你說你在邁阿密表演?
You say you perform in the Miami area?
到處都去
Oh, si. Here, there, you know.
我在古巴是魔術師。他們都叫我「蠻牛」魔術師
l was a magician in Cuba. They used to call me Manuelito the Magician.
米拉，開個門
Mira, can you please open?
- 我沒穿衣服 - 我是傑克弗理的好友
- I'm not dressed. - I'm a good friend of Jack Foley.
- 你認識傑克?  - 你是誰?
- You know Jack? - Who are you?
荷西奇裡諾
Jose Chirino.
也許你聽過傑克叫我奇諾。我就是
Or maybe you heard Jack call me Chino. Bueno, I'm the same guy.
叫他等等：你要穿衣服
Tell him he has to wait in the hall. You have to get dressed. Say it loud.
在外面等。你要穿衣服
Wait in the hall. You have to get dressed.
告訴我哪裡找得到傑克，我就不再煩你
Mira, mira, you tell me where l could find Jack and I don't bother you no more.
好啦！拜託
Now, come on, please! Hello?
- 我不知道他在哪 - 我幫過傑克逃獄
- I don't know where he is. - I'm the guy that helped Jack escape from prison.
- 米拉, 打開這該死的門…… - 我要叫警察了
- Mira, please open this fucking door-- - I'm gonna call the police.
為什麼要那樣對傑克的朋友?
Cono, why you gonna do that to a friend, man? A partner to Jack?
夠了
That's it! That's it!
米拉。拜託！
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow, ow! Cono, mira, please!
- 阿黛爾！阿黛爾！ - 手給我
- Adele! Adele! - Give me your hand.
- 你不是阿黛爾 - 聯邦警察，你被拘捕了
- You not Adele! - I'm a federal marshal, and you're under arrest.
把皮包給我，阿黛兒
- Get my bag, Adele. - Oh.
我想這有些誤會
Mira, please, please. l think there's a misunderstanding here.
好皮包
Can you-- you got nice bag.
這件事就算了吧。我回家……
Mira, let's say we just forget about it, okay? We forget about this, l go home--
- 閉嘴！ - 誰該死地教你那樣做?
- Shut up. - Owwww! Who the hell taught you how to do that?
- 另一隻手給我 - 好
- Give me your other hand. - Okay, okay. Ay, cono.
我得去小便
Ohhhh! l gotta go make pee-pee.
Ohhhhh! Owww!
你好過份
Wow! You are mean!
我要找律師。你侵犯我的人權
Look, I'm gonna call my lawyer. This is-- What do they call that? Human rights violation.
- 丹尼爾伯波頓 - 凱倫西思柯
- Ay, cono. - Daniel Burdon, please. Karen Sisco.
米拉, 阿黛兒 可以問個問題嗎
Mira, Adele, Adele. Can l ask you a question, please?
記得你表演的那個魔術嗎?
You know that trick you do?
凱倫?你在哪?我一直在找你
Karen? Where are you? l've been trying to reach you.
他們把你鋸成一半時
When you in the box and they saw you in half?
- 我在阿黛兒德利西家 - 是魔術呀
- I'm at Adele Delisi's. - It's magic.
我們已經找過她啦 死巷一條
We already talked to her. That's a dead end.
如果我帶奇裡諾回去，你會讓我加入特勤小組?
l was just wondering, if l brought in Chirino, would you let me be on the task force?
- 當然 - 他們插入鋸子，再分開盒子
- Yeah, sure, Karen. - Then they put the saw through, and they separate it.
不過你怎麼動腳趾頭?
- And that's it. Ta da. - But how do you twinkle your toes? I don't get that.
如果你帶奇裡諾回來，就可以加入特勤小組
You bring Chirino in, and you can be on the task force.
- 這就是我想知道的 - 好
- That's all l wanted to know. - Good.
別管那個前妻了
Now, would you forget about the ex-wife,
回亞當斯旅館去
and get over to the Adams Hotel?
知道了
- You got it. - Then they open it up--
不！
- No! No! - Come on.
- 就這樣而已 - 是假腳
- And then that's it. - Fake legs.
假腳? 那你怎麼……
- Mmm. - Fake legs? How you gonna--
- 謝啦, 阿黛兒
- Ay! Cono. - Thanks, Adele.
如果是假腳，怎麼能動呢?
How do they twinkle their toes, then, if it's fake, mira?
亞當斯旅館
我們到底特律第一件事就是找葛蘭
First thing we do, we get to Detroit, we find Glenn,
然後把他扔出窗去
and we find a window to throw him out of.
我想，如果我是葛蘭……
l was thinkin', if l was Glenn, and l was up there...
動了瑞利的腦筋，會去哪裡
to take down the Ripper, where would l go?
但如果你是葛蘭，就根本不會動腦筋
'Cept that if you were Glenn, you wouldn't be thinkin'.
記得史努比米勒，他的好兄弟?
Remember Snoopy Miller, his old pal from the joint?
史努比，我以為他早已死了
Snoop? l figured he'd be brain-dead by now.
史努比不再打拳了
Nah, Snoop doesn't box anymore.
葛蘭說他在克朗克做幾個拳擊手的經紀人
Glenn told me that he's managing some fighters out at the Kronk.
- 拿到鑰匙了? - 他們在613房
- Did you get the key? - They're in room 613.
兩個人在外面，守著前後門
All right. l want two men outside, front and back.
康諾、傑森，上六樓，掩護走廊兩端。
Conroy, Jamison, go on up to six, cover both ends of the hall.
你先走，你殿後
You're primary. You're secondary.
你把哨
And you're point man.
- 你要用撞門樁嗎? - 對。幹嘛?
- You gonna use a ram? - Yeah. Why?
經理的門是鐵的
The manager's door is metal.
說不定全是
You know what l mean, they might all be.
樁打在鐵門上製造噪音而已
A ram on a metal door makes a lot of noise for what good it does.
我的6A746727里有破鎖彈
l got a shock lock round for my shotgun that oughta do the trick.
好。隨便
Fine. Whatever.
二樓。謝謝
Two, please.
你
You.
走樓梯吧
Fuck it. Let's take the stairs. Karen--
待在大廳，監視電梯
Take the radio. Stay down here in the lobby and watch the elevator.
- 丹尼爾，我要上去 - 你要待在車上也行
- Daniel, l want to go upstairs. - Well, you can wait in the car if you want to.
如果你看到弗理和柏格出現，你會怎麼做?
Now, you see Foley and Bragg coming behind us. What do you do?
- 呼叫你嗎? - 然後讓他們上來
- Call and tell you? - And you let them come up.
不要自行逮捕他們。明白嗎?
You don't try to make the bust yourself. You understand?
是這樓嗎，女士?
ls this your floor, ma'am?
噢，是的
Oh. Oh, yes.
抱歉。謝謝
Yes, it is. I'm sorry. Thank you.
注意，我們接近目標門口了
Be advised we are approaching the door.
注意，要炸開門了
Be advised we are going to blow the door.
上樓嗎?
Going up?
我以為是上樓
Shit, l thought l was going up.
她一直注視著我
She just looked right at me.
- 誰？ - 凱倫
- Who? - Karen.
凱倫西斯柯?
- Karen Sisco? - Yeah.
她在大廳
She's in the lobby.
- 她在大廳？ - 對。
- She's in the lobby? - Yeah.
如果他們知道我住哪，就知道我開什麼車。 我們得棄車
They know where l live, no doubt they know what l drive. We gotta dump this car.
她就坐在那，看著我
She just sat there, looking right at me.
他們不在上面。睜大眼睛
Karen, they're not up here. Keep your eyes open.
凱倫，你在聽嗎？
Karen? Karen, are you there?
跟你揮手？
He waved at you?
我肯定他有
Couldn't swear to it, but I'm pretty sure he did.
- 你也揮手了？ - 來不及了
- Did you wave back? - l didn't have time.
可是我想你會的
l imagine you would have, though.
巴蒂的姊姊，維珍柏格
Buddy's sister, Regina Mary Bragg,
今早接到兩通巴蒂從底特律打的電話
got two calls from Buddy in Detroit this morning.
她通知波頓
She calls Burdon. She's also the one who called Burdon...
- 他還拿到巴蒂的住址 - 又怎樣?
- and gave him Buddy's address. - So?
在她告發他後，為什麼還跟她聯絡?
So what l want to know is why he still calls her even after she turned him in.
他不記恨嘛
He doesn't seem to hold a grudge. What l want to know is why,
如果他們在北方有大計劃，為什麼弗理待在邁阿密這麼久
they got such a big score up north, did Foley hang around Miami for so long?
- 你覺得呢？ - 我不想說
- Any thoughts on that? - None l'd like to share.
- 回來後我再打電話給你  - 好吧
- l'll call you when l get in. - Okay.
底特律
Hey
真浪費時間
Time is truly wasting
我不單只做買賣和管理拳擊手
You know, I don't just deal product and manage fighters no more.
從上次見面後，很多事都變了
A lot's changed since the last time you seen me, man. It's like l've, uh,
我把自己變得多元化
vertically integrated myself, you know, diversified and shit,
我偶爾會偷東西
and now I'm into the occasional grand larceny,
闖空門，做那些鳥事
- home invasion, shit like that. - Huh.
白波是我這裡的跑腿
White Boy Bob right there's my all-around man, you know.
需要時，還可以是保鏢、司機
He's my personal bodyguard when l feel like l need one, driver, shit like that.
小心看路啊，白波!幹嘛回頭?
Yo, man, watch the road, White Boy! What you lookin' back here for?
- 耶 - 耶
- Yeah. - Yeah.
我喜歡這部車，葛蘭
- l like this car, Glenn. - Yeah.
你偷了部好車，小子
You stole a good one, boy.
我們可以在瑞利家附近繞……
You can roll around in Ripley's neighborhood up there in Bloomfield Hills,
不用怕私人警衛
not get sweated by the private security.
不會有警察當跟屁蟲。不錯吧
Ain't gonna have no police on our ass, nothing like that. It's nice, man.
是!
Yeah.
你還沒說要怎麼幹這件事
Oh, hey, so you still haven't said how you want to do this thing.
接到另一個兄弟後，我就一起講
Oh, I'm gonna tell you that as soon as we get one other brother I'm gonna need, uh,
肯尼，那是墨塞的弟弟……
Kenneth-- that's Moselle's brother--
跟白波一道
along with White Boy right there.
- 什麼！ - 到了，白波
- What? - All right, here we go, White Boy.
那個消防員是誰？
Uh, who's the fireman?
肯尼那狗小子
Ken dog.
- 嘿? - 怎麼樣，大老千?
- What's up, brother-in-law? - What's happenin', hustler?
你怕聞煙味?
Hey, man. This cigarette gonna bother you, Mo?
熄了它。肯尼，這是葛蘭
Yeah, put that thing out, all right? Ken, this is Glenn.
葛蘭，這是肯尼，我跟你提過的傢伙
- Glenn, that's Kenny, the dude l was tellin' you about. - Hi.
你就是那個要幫我們打劫有錢白佬的人
You're the one gonna help us rip off that rich white dude?
- 就是他 - 幫你?
- Yeah, that's him. - Help you?
開車，白波
Go ahead, White Boy.
等等，看……
Um, whoa, wait a minute, um, look--
莫瑞，是我讓你加入計劃
Maurice, l am letting you in on this gig,
不是……
not--
你剛問我們要怎麼做
- You just asked how we gonna do it, right? - Yeah.
我現在告訴你。我們是專家
Well, I'm telling you how, man. We the experts.
我擔心的是你，葛蘭
Person I'm worried about is you, Glenn.
我？
- Me? - Yeah.
你真的可以幹這檔子事，還是說說而已?
Can you step up and actually do this shit instead of just talking the talk?
幹什麼？
Do what?
打劫我挑中的房子
Walk into this house l got picked out.
幹掉這個以前我和他交易過的黑鬼人妖
Do this cross-dressing nigger named Eddie Solomon l used to sell to.
- 他自己做買賣 - 什麼事？甚麼時候？
- Been dealing on his own. - What? When, man?
現在。你以為做這檔子事是幹嘛?
Shit, right now, son. What you think all this shit is for?
我不用向你證明什麼
I don't need to prove shit to you, man, okay?
瑞利的事是我的事。要不要做隨你
The Ripley job is my job. You're either in or you're not.
你想揍惹你生氣的毒販
You wanna go pop some crack dealer pissed you off, man,
那是你的問題，不是我的
- that is your problem, not mine, fuck! - Glenn,
我知道你酷
l know you supposed to be cool and everything, okay,
但不要用這種口氣對我說話
but you ain't got to give me no tone of voice.
你不高興我說的隨時可以走
You don't like what I'm sayin', you just bounce the fuck out this whip anywhere up in here.
我想我們都忘了這是我的事
Okay, l think we're forgetting that this is my whip.
我提起的
l brought it up.
聽著。我說這是我的車，就是我的
Shit. Hey, come on, man. lf l say this is my car, you know this is my car.
你自己去找另一部
You just get yourself another one.
不管你要不要，我們都決定進行
lf l say we in on this Ripley shit, we in on it, with or without your punk ass.
如果我要你幹掉這個混蛋
And if l say you gonna walk up in this house and do this motherfucker...
來證明你有種
so l can see if you got any balls or not,
你猜你該怎麼做?
guess what else you gonna do?
到了
We're here.
綁緊褲子，小子
Tighten up your panties, boy.
鐵鋸。我來拿
- Hacksaw. Okay, l'll take that. - Oh, yeah.
斧頭
- Hatchet, man. - Hatchet?
拿斧頭幹嘛
What are you gonna do with a hatchet?
去好好修理那混蛋
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Let's get some fire to that ass.
你要．45口徑還是手槍?
Look here. You want the .45 or the Glock?
葛蘭？
Glenn?
狗屎，小子
Shit, boy.
比你想得更糟，對吧？
lt was worse than you thought it was gonna be, huh?
現在你跟壞人一夥了
You with the bad boys now, baby.
走吧
Let's go.
你認為怎麼樣？
What do you think?
我想葛蘭很驚奇，我們有了另一個兄弟
l think Glenn opened his big mouth and now we got ourselves another partner.
想加入
Hey, Studs, how ya doin'?
你們在這幹嘛?
Jesus Christ, what are you guys doin' here?
你在等我們嗎?
Weren't you expecting us?
終於有人踩了你的墨鏡
Where's your sunglasses? Somebody finally step on 'em for ya?
- 我不知道 - 你的襯衫上是誰的血?
- I don't know. - Whose blood you got on your shirt?
那些傢伙瘋了
Listen, man, these guys are crazy.
史努比 那些傢伙瘋了
- Snoop! - Shit.
我們有麻煩？
We have a problem here?
傑克弗理，有名的銀行大盜
Jack Foley, famous bank robber.
史努比米勒，有名的拳手經紀人
Snoopy Miller, famous fight thrower.
報上說你從佛羅里達逃獄
Seems l read somewhere that you broke out of a prison down in Florida.
- 是那樣的？ - 那裡全是低級的人，史努比
- ls that right? - They got a low class of people there, Snoop.
再叫一次，你頭會撞壁
Hey, you call him that again I'm gonna put your head through the wall.
什麼? 你說「史努比?」
What? You mean ''Snoop''?
白波是說沒人叫我史努比了
Nobody calls me Snoop or Snoopy anymore is what White Boy Bob is trying to tell you.
他只是有點粗魯。你懂嘛?
He's just a little crude with it. You know what l mean?
我全拋腦後了，夥伴
Nah, l left all that behind me, partner.
你叫這白癡「白波?」
But you call this bozo ''White Boy.''
白波曾是個拳手
White Boy Bob used to be a fighter.
你現在做甚麼，白波?
Oh, so tell me, what do you do now, White Boy Bob,
除了射掉你的大嘴巴?
outside of shoot your big mouth off?
- 像在監獄大院一樣 - 就這樣
- Like being back in the yard, isn't it? - Yeah, just like it.
不准退出
Nobody backing down or nothing.
誰要退出，誰就是膽小鬼
You back down, you just a pussy.
- 為什麼你們全在底特律? - 葛蘭沒告訴你?
- Why y'all in Detroit anyway, up here in the cold? - Glenn didn't tell you?
- 葛蘭?什麼? - 我以為你們被抓了
- Glenn? What? - l thought you guys were busted.
為什麼?因為你留我們站在路旁
Why's that? 'Cause you left us standing on the side of the road?
噢
Whoops.
聽著，我不知道葛蘭答應了什麼
Look, Snoop, I don't know what Glenn promised you,
現在計劃是
or what you think you're going to get out of this-- here's the deal:
從瑞利那裡得到的錢我和巴蒂拿一半
Buddy and l, we're going to take half of anything we get off of Ripley.
其他的，你們去分
Anything else, you guys are allowed to cut up any way you want.
為什麼不到外面談?
Oh. Why don't we talk about this outside, man?
- 這裡舒服。很溫暖 - 這裡大概90度
- Nice in here. It's warm. - Warm? It's like 90 degrees in here, man.
有時有100度以上
Sometimes it's 100 up in this mug.
因為伊曼喜歡保持這樣
That's the way Emmanuel like to keep it.
把他的拳手養得瘦瘦兇兇的像湯米賀恩一樣
Keep his fighters mean and lean like Tommy Hearns. Ain't that right, Kenny?
我要去個地方
l got someplace to be anyway, so tell you what:
星期五晚上來看比賽
Why don't y'all come by the fights Friday night?
我們坐下來，慢慢談。討論一下計劃
We'll sit down, chop it up, you know, look it over.
- 州立劇院 - 到時見
- State Theater. - All right. We'll see you then.
拿槍打劫銀行一定要很大的勇氣
So it must take a lot of balls to walk into a bank and stick it up with a gun, huh?
我不知道。我從沒用過槍
I don't know. l never used a gun before in my life.
你開玩笑
You're kidding.
如果你做得巧妙，你會得到意想不到的東西
You'd be surprised what all you can get if you ask for it the right way.
就因為你，我不敢把錢存在銀行
Well, you're the reason, my friend, that I don't keep all my money in the bank.
那你放在哪裡?
So where do you keep your money, Dick?
我是說那些沒加工過的鑽石
Talking about all those uncut diamonds you told about.
- 我知道你在說什麼 - 你有膽量
- l know what you're talking about. - You're the one with balls.
跟葛蘭說過嗎?
Say something like that to somebody like Glenn?
得了，誰會相信葛蘭
Glenn? Come on, nobody's going to believe Glenn.
- 你相信他嗎? - 我不
- Do you believe Glenn? - Uh, no, I don't.
就算是真的，他也要知道我藏在哪裡
Besides, even if it was true, he'd still have to know where l keep 'em, wouldn't he?
你跟他說藏在你家
Doesn't have to know anything. You told him you keep 'em in your house.
我家很大。你要在這兒待多久?
It's a very big house. So, how much longer you in here for?
22個月，三天，兩個鐘頭
Uh, 22 months, three days, two hours.
- 為什麼? - 因為我可以雇像你這樣的人
- Why? - 'Cause l could use a guy like you.
一個知道怎麼才能做得巧妙的人
Somebody that knows how to ask for things in the right way.
我是說在你出獄後
I'm talking about when you're out of here.
你不可能老打劫銀行，對不對?
After all, you can't rob banks forever, can you?
- 我可不是一個上班族 - 誰是?
- I'm not exactly a nine to five type. - Who is?
我以為人人都喜歡艾迪
l thought everybody liked Eddie.
- 你好嗎，雷? - 我冷死了
- How you doin', Ray? - I'm freezing.
我可是開始暖和起來了
But I'm getting warmer.
除了上次我們合作很愉快以外
So listen, other than we had so much fun the last time we worked together,
為什麼找我，不找聯邦調查局
you want to tell me why you're coming to me instead of the F.B.l.?
調查局只會叫我去買咖啡
l go to the F.B.l., the first thing they're gonna do is send me to get some coffee.
你知道嗎?你是對的
You know what? You're right.
去年緝毒局想要抓葛蘭說他持有毒品
Ray, about a year ago, D.E.A. had a guy, Glenn Michaels, on possession with intent.
- 但沒有成功 - 開車
- Listen, is that your car? Find out whose it is. - They couldn't make it stick.
葛蘭說他要來底特律看朋友
ln his statement, he said he was coming to Detroit to see a friend...
談有關工作的事
about job opportunities, if you can believe that.
- 什麼朋友 - 莫瑞米勒，
- What was the name of the friend? - Maurice Miller,
渾名叫史努比，以前是拳手
also known as Snoopy, used to be a prizefighter.
我知道史努比，這人很難搞
l know Snoopy. He's a fucking wack job.
在西部
He thinks he's Sugar Ray Leonard, hangs out over on the west side...
和另外幾個頭號笨蛋一起
with a couple of other first-rate nut cases.
- 我要地址 - 27-10
- Well, I'm gonna need a last known address. - 2710 coming in.
- 你要什麼? - 最近的地址
- You're gonna need what? - A last known address.
那是你的車嗎?
That your car?
我不喜歡你和米勒單獨見面
No way. I don't want you talking to Miller alone.
得了，雷，我是聯邦人員，我有槍
Come on, Ray. I'm a federal officer. l can handle myself. I'm armed.
明天我再打電話告訴你地址
l'll call you tomorrow with the address.
謝謝你，雷
Thank you, Raymond.
你看報紙了嗎?
You see the paper?
- 她很上鏡頭 - 除了這
- It's a terrific shot of her. - Outside of that.
我不認為她來此跟我們有關係
Doesn't say what she's doing here, but I don't think it has anything to do with us.
她是來渡假，因為這裡狗屎天氣
She came up here on her vacation because she likes shitty weather.
我想她是來抓葛蘭的
Nah, l think she's after Glenn.
那女的在嗎
The girl still there?
除非你給錢，否則她們不會留下過夜
They don't stay the whole night, Jack, unless you pay for it.
- 你有沒有告訴你姐姐?  - 有，我剛打了。她為我祈禱
- Did you tell your sister? - Yeah, l just hung up. She prayed for me.
- 你打了多久? - 兩個小時
- Mm-hmm. And how long were you on the phone with her? - Two hours.
- 你跟那女的呢? - 四十五分鐘
- And how long were you with the girl? - 45 minutes.
你跟你姐姐談到瑞利了嗎?
You didn't tell your sister about Ripley, did you?
別再提我姐姐了
Look, Jack, just forget about my sister, okay?
如果凱倫盯著葛蘭，我們就慘了
Now, if Karen Sisco is tailing Glenn, we're fucked.
明晚我們都會被抓
Tomorrow night at the fights, we all get picked up.
我們先去劇院，看看
Why don't we just drive by where we're meeting tonight, check it out.
再去瑞利家
And we'll go by Ripley's too, while we're at it.
好吧
- Yeah, all right. - All right.
- 安瑟旅館，我能否為你服務? - 請找凱倫西思柯
- Athenaeum Hotel, how may l help you? - Karen Sisco, please.
- 好西部旅館 - 請找凱倫西思柯
- Hello, Best Western. - Karen Sisco, please.
- 莫塞米勒嗎? - 你找誰?
- Moselle Miller? - What do you want?
- 我找莫瑞 - 你找到他，說他那隻狗死了
- I'm looking for Maurice. - You find him, tell him the dog got run over.
我沒有伙食錢了
I'm out of grocery money.
- 你在和誰說話? - 有個女的找莫瑞
- Moselle, who you talkin' to? - Lady lookin' for Maurice.
- 她要什麼 - 她沒說
- What does she want? - Hasn't said.
- 那不是莫瑞? - 那是我弟弟肯尼
- That's not Maurice? - That's Kenneth, my brother. He's talkin' on the phone.
- 問她找他幹什麼 - 你去問她!
- Ask her what she want with him! - You ask her!
- 莫瑞的事與我無關 - 你媽的對
- Maurice business is none of my business. - Yeah, you damn right.
劇場? 誰在比賽?
State Theater, huh? Who's fightin'?
黑鬼，怎麼樣?
Nigger, what?
我在找一個莫瑞認識的人
I'm looking for somebody l think Maurice knows.
你不是緩刑小組來的吧?
You're not with probation, one of those?
- 不是 - 你是律師嗎?
- No. - You a lawyer?
不是。我在找葛蘭麥克
No, I'm not. I'm looking for somebody named Glenn Michaels.
我不認識什麼葛蘭
Glenn? I don't know any Glenn.
他說他去年11月待在這裡
He said he stayed here last November.
- 在這房子裡? - 他說他和莫瑞在一塊
- Here in this house? - He said he stayed with Maurice.
連莫瑞都不常來了
Well, he ain't even here that much.
我想知道他到那去了
l'd like to know where he goes, but at the same time,
又不想知道，你懂嗎?
I don't wanna know, you understand?
我懂
Yeah.
- 你的狗死了? - 被車碾死的了
- You say your dog was killed? - Got run over by a car.
- 它叫什麼? - 它是母的，叫塔菲
- What'd you call him? - Was a she. Named Tuffy.
你想我在那裡可以找到莫瑞?
Where do you think l might find Maurice, Moselle?
我不知道。健身房?拳擊場?
I don't know. The gym, the fights.
他從不錯過拳賽。明天晚上劇場裡有拳賽
l know he don't miss the fights. They're havin' some tomorrow down at the State Theater.
- 他以前都帶我去 - 劇場
- He used to take me. - The State Theater.
你為什麼問一大堆有關莫瑞的事?
Why you askin' all these questions about Maurice?
她在找一個叫葛蘭的人
She lookin' for a man name of Glenn.
我問你了嗎?辦你的事去
Did l ask you? Go on and do something with yourself, Moselle.
你去給我們拿點吃的來
Why don't you take your ass to Dot and Etta's and get us some shrimp or somethin'?
你打拳
You are a fight?
你怎麼知道？
How do you know that?
我看得出來
I can't tell.
我是
Yeah, I was.
直到我的視網膜剝落了二次
'Til l got my retina detached two times.
- 你打那一級?中量級? - 輕量級
- What'd you fight, about middleweight? - Nah, light.
超中量級，等我長壯一點
Super middleweight, once my body developed.
- 你打那一級?羽量級? - 蠅量級
- What you go about, what, a bantam? - Flyweight.
黑鬼，怎樣?該知道你的等級
Nigger, what? You know your divisions, huh?
你喜歡打拳嗎?你喜歡動粗嗎?
Do you like the fights? You like the rough stuff?
我想你一定喜歡
Yeah, l bet you do.
想不想下來幹一場?
You like to get down and tussle a little bit?
像從前我和塔菲一樣
Like me and Tuffy, before she got run over.
我們常在地上扭在一塊
We used to get down on the floor and tussle all the time.
我告訴它「塔菲」，你這只好狗這個好吃的給你」
l'd say to her, ''You a good bitch, Tuffy. Here's a treat for ya.''
我給塔菲所有母狗都愛的，你知道是什麼嗎?
And l give Tuffy what all good bitches love best, and you know what that is?
知道那是什麼嗎?一塊骨頭
Know what that is? A bone.
我也會給你一塊好的骨頭
l'll give you a good bone too, girl.
你不是我喜歡的那種人
You're not my type.
那話對我沒意義
No, that shit don't mean nothin' to me.
- 我掏出我的大傢伙…… - 我得走了
- l let the monster out, you gonna do what it wants. - l gotta go, Kenneth.
- 說不定我們會再見面 - 不，我們先幹一場
- Maybe we'll see each other again. - No, no, we gonna tussle first.
Awww!
媽的!那是什麼鬼東西?
Damn it! What the fuck was that?
你想幹一場。我們來干
You wanted to tussle. We tussled.
那是個大房子
That's a big ass house.
這地方就像監獄
Place almost looks like a prison.
他可真有一套，複雜的保安系統
No doubt he's got some serious security system.
到時候，我們去敲門看他要不要敘舊
Time comes, we go up, knock on the door, see if he wants to talk about old times.
- 太簡單了 - 酷
- You know, the easy way. - Cool.
有史努比和那一身肉的混蛋他會讓我們進去嗎?
Think he'll let us in, we got the Snoop and that musclebound asshole with us?
沒有別人
Nobody's gonna be with us.
明晚我們去看拳賽聽聽史努比的大計劃
l say we go to the fights tomorrow night, see what Snoopy's big plan is,
然後我們比他快一步
then we go in, ahead of him, alone.
好主意
Oh, l can dig it.
當我們去逍遙的時候讓葛蘭去應付史努
Let Glenn deal with the Snoop, while we off livin' the good life.
你知道有誰做了一大筆
Good life. Buddy, you know anybody who's done one last big score...
然後就逍遙法外了?
and then gone on to live the good life?
我們也有可能空手而歸
Look, Jack, there's a chance we'll walk out of here with nothin'.
我看，聽天由命吧
l say, let fate decide.
命運?你是什麼，他媽的達賴喇嘛?
Let fate decide? What are you, the fuckin' Dalai Lama now?
是我姊姊
Nah, man, it's my sister.
我姊姊相信命運不相信地獄
My sister believes in fate but not hell.
她不再為喪失靈魂的人禱告
That's why she stopped praying for all the lost souls,
雖然你不肯再聽贖罪之類的話
since you don't hear that much about purgatory anymore.
但她每天仍為巴蒂禱告希望他不出事
But every day, she asks her boss to pray that Buddy don't fuck up.
你認為呢?
l mean, what do you think?
你認為地獄存在嗎?
- Well-- - You think there's a hell?
葛雷茲監獄就是
Yeah, it's called the Glades Correctional lnstitute.
我決不回到像那樣的地方去
I'm sure as shit not going back there or any place like it.
他們用槍對著你，你就得去
They put a gun on you, you'll go, brother.
那怕有槍，你還是有選擇的餘地
They put a gun on you, you still have a choice.
所以，弗理先生
So, Mr. Foley,
瑞利先生和我長談過你在公司上班的事
Mr. Ripley and l have had a long discussion about your role in the company,
他覺得你在邁阿密上班會愉快些
and it was his feeling you'd be happiest working down here in Miami.
- 怎麼樣？ - 好極了
- How's that sound to you? - Sounds great.
好。你穿42號加長的，對嗎?
Good. You're about a 42 long, right?
我大概是穿42號
l uh, I'm about a 42--
像，42號普通的
like, 42 regular.
- 穿穿看合不合身 - 這是什麼?
- Okay, let's see how she fits. - What is that?
你的制服
Your uniform.
我的制服?
My uniform.
弗理先生 弗理先生
Mr. Foley. Mr. Foley!
先生! 請等等
Sir, sir. Excuse me, sir.
Sir! Sir, excuse me!
- 你不能進去! - 有警衛？
- You can't go in there! - Are you fucking kidding me? A security guard?
- 你搞什麼，昏了頭啦? - 嘿，別發火!
- What are you, stoned? - Hey, hey! Take it easy!
沒關係，佩姬。沒事了
It's all right, Peggy. It's under control.
聽我說
You know something?
我不確定你會來。但我知道如果你來了
l wasn't sure that you'd show up here, but l was very sure if you did,
你也會把這差事扔到我臉上
you'd throw this job in my face.
讓我告訴你吧
Let me tell you something.
到今天為止你所做的
Every single thing you've done with your life up until this point...
都沒有任何意義
in the real world means nothing.
一點意義也沒有
Less than nothing.
你是個搶銀行的
You're a bank robber.
那是個見不得人的本事
That's not a very marketable skill.
誰看過搶銀行的
We don't see a lot of old bank robbers walking around...
領養老金了?
with a pension plan, now do we?
我想你懂這個道理所以你才會來這裡
l think you know this. That's why you're here.
今天，我給你……
Today, l've offered you...
一個爛工作，爛薪水
a lousy job with a lousy wage.
你要好一點的工作?證明你能改頭換面給我看
You want something better? Why don't you show me you can change?
我才會給你好點的差事
Then l'll offer you something better, a lot better.
在這之前，老兄，你得去賺
But until then, my friend, you'll have to earn it.
怎麼賺，狄克?像你這樣?
How, Dick? The way you earn it?
討個開公司的富婆
Married some rich broad owns the company,
賣了公司，再和她離婚?
selling it off a piece at a time then divorcing her?
說什麼「自食其力」的狗屎?
What's this Knute Rockne ''pull yourself up by the bootstraps'' bullshit?
在監獄裡，像你這種人?
Back in prison, a guy like you in a place like that?
一定會被整得稀巴爛
You were ice cream for freaks. A goddamned dumpling.
莫瑞和其他的傢伙會要你的命
Maurice and a dozen other guys would have bled you till you had nothing.
打死你。是我救了你的狗命
Until you were nothing. l saved your ass!
抱歉我不願坐椅子上
So you'll pardon me if I don't want to sit on a fucking stool all day,
還要說「請簽名」或「你不能停在這裡」
and say, ''Sign in here, please,'' or ''Hey, pal, you can't park here.''
我不能幹這種事，狄克
All right, Dick? I can't fuckin' do it, Dick!
你讓我失望
- I'm disappointed in you. - You wanna--
又來了。他答應了你們這些人什麼?
Oh, here we go. What job did he promise you boys?
- 我們有二種辦法 - 什麼辦法?
- There's two ways we can do this. - Yeah, what are they?
山托斯銀行
我必需買雙好鞋以及明天用的東西
Hey, Buddy, l gotta get a better pair of shoes and some things for tomorrow.
我們一會兒見
Drop me off by the Ren Center and we'll hook up later?
好
Yeah, okay.
我最好打個電話給我姊姊
l better go call my sister.
要喝點什麼？
Can l get you anything?
我要波本和水
Yeah, l'll have a bourbon, please. Water back.
好
Okay.
你為什麼不問我們還要什麼?
Hey, Tad, why don't you do us again, please?
席萊，那女士的酒算我們的
Oh, and, Celeste, put the lady's drink on our bill.
- 他們要請你喝杯酒 - 我想也是
- They want to buy your drink for you. - Yeah, l get that.
- 告訴他們我情願自己付 - 好的
- Tell them l'd rather pay for my own. - Okay.
我來問問看
l'll find out.
對不起
Excuse me.
我和同事們打了個賭
My associates and l, we made a little bet...
看看你是幹哪一行的?
on what you do for a living.
我打贏了。我叫菲利普
And l won. Hi. I'm Phillip.
菲利普，我只想安靜的喝一杯酒走
lf it's okay with you, Phillip, l'd rather just have a quiet drink and leave.
難道你不想知道我是怎麼知道的?
Don't you want to know what l guessed? How l know what you do for a living?
我並不想對你不禮貌，我只是想清靜一下
Really, Phillip, I don't want to be rude. l just want to be left alone.
她有點冷淡
It's a little cold over there.
我知道你為什麼這麼沮喪
Excuse me. l think l know why you're depressed.
我能把我的意見告訴你嗎?
lf l can offer my observation.
我猜你是新來的推銷員
See, l got a hunch you're the new sales rep,
你的客戶並不十分滿意，因為處理他們戶頭的
and the client's not exactly knocked out by the fact that a young lady--
竟然是一位像你這麼年輕的小姐
even one as stunning as yourself-- is handling the account.
我猜得很對吧?
Am l close?
我是安迪
I'm Andy.
我們都是廣告業的，今天早上才從紐約飛來的
We're all ad guys. Flew in this morning from the apple-- New York.
替「河邊路人」酒廠做廣告
Came in to pitch Hiram Walker Distillery.
給新的瑪格麗特雞尾酒做試售計劃
Little test market campaign for the new margarita mix.
那真的是很有意思，比方說
It's really pretty interesting. We take this, um,
麥克司…西裔的土匪
Mex-- um, Hispanic bandito...
掛著子彈帶，拿了傢伙戴了一個大帽子
with his bullet belts and everything, and the big Chihuahua hat,
然後他拔出六發子彈的槍
and he pulls out his six-guns,
- 我背後的那些傢伙 - 安迪
- and these guys back here-- - Andy.
誰管這些狗屎?
Really. Who gives a shit?
- 要不要告訴我怎麼回事兒? - 滾開，安迪
- Do you want to tell me what happened? - Beat it, Andy.
安迪
Andy.
你做了什麼?
What'd you do?
- 我能請你喝杯酒嗎？ - 好，來一杯
- Can l buy you a drink? - Yeah, l'd love one.
坐下
Sit down.
我是蓋瑞
I'm Gary.
我是席萊
I'm Celeste.
- 只有一個女侍 - 我可以到吧檯去
- lt takes forever to get a drink. There's only one waitress. - l can go to the bar.
- 別去 - 他們煩你了？
- Oh, don't go. - Are those guys bothering you?
沒事，你剛到嗎?
No, they're fine. l mean, you just got here.
來，喝一點
Here, help yourself.
- 你喜歡波本酒? - 我喜歡
- You like bourbon? - l love it.
席萊，告訴我，你是幹哪一行的?
We got that out of the way. Tell me, Celeste, what do you do for a living?
我是個推銷員，來拜訪一位客戶
I'm a sales rep, and l came here to call on a customer,
因為我是女的，他們就刁難我
but they gave me a hard time 'cause I'm a girl.
你是這麼想你自己的嗎?
ls that how you think of yourself?
- 推銷員？ - 女人
- As a sales rep? - As a girl.
- 我無所謂 - 我喜歡你的髮型
- Yeah, I don't have a problem with it. - l like your hair.
- 我喜歡你的打扮 - 這是我第二喜歡的一套衣服
- l like your outfit. - Actually, this is my second favorite outfit.
我最喜歡的一套已經被糟蹋了只好扔了
l had a first favorite, but it got ruined and l had to get rid of it.
- 真的？ - 臭臭的
- You did? - lt smelled.
- 洗了也沒用 - 對
- Really? Having it cleaned didn't help? - No.
蓋瑞，你做什麼的?
So tell me, Gary, what do you do for a living?
- 你還要這樣繼續多久? - 先別說甚麼
- How far do you want to go with this? - Don't say anything yet.
沒用的，我們就是我們
I don't think it works if we're somebody else.
蓋瑞和席萊，他們知道甚麼?
l mean, Gary and Celeste, what do they know about anything?
- 我沒玩過這種遊戲 - 這不是遊戲
- Well, this is your game, l've never played before. - It's not a game.
不是你玩的遊戲
It's not something you play.
對你有意義嗎?
Well, does this make any sense to you?
不須要有意義，是自然發生的
lt doesn't have to. It's something that happens.
像在街上第一次看到一個人，你以為你們會擦肩而過，
It's like seeing someone for the first time-- like you could be passing on the street,
你們彼此看了幾秒……
and you look at each other and for a few seconds...
就覺得你們彼此靈犀相通
there's this kind of a recognition-- like you both know something.
但下一刻，那人就走了
The next moment, the person's gone,
也來不及做甚麼
and it's too late to do anything about it.
你會永遠記得，你錯過了某些東西
And you always remember it, because it was there, and you let it go,
你告訴自己，「假如我停下來了呢?」
and you think to yourself, ''What if l had stopped? lf l had said something?''
「假如……」
''What if?''
這種事一生中只會發生幾次
And it may only happen a few times in your life.
- 或一次 - 或一次
- Or once. - Or once.
你怎麼找到我的?
How'd you find me?
啊恩
Uh--
我在樓下打到你的房間
Called your room from downstairs.
哦
Oh.
如果我接電話，你要說甚麼?
And if l had answered, what were you gonna say?
說我是誰，你記得我嗎?要不要一起喝一杯？
l would say who l was, and do you remember me, and want to meet for a drink?
記得你嗎？我來這兒就為找你
lf l remembered you. l came here looking for you.
然後我會說好。但你知道
All right, so then l would have said yes, but for all you know,
我也可能讓霹靂小組等著你，你為什麼信任我?
l could have had a SWAT team waiting for you-- why would you trust me?
值得冒險
lt'd be worth the risk.
- 你喜歡冒險 - 你也是
- You like taking risks. - So do you.
遲早……
You know, sooner or later--
你真的穿那套套裝
You really wear that suit.
這不是你想說的
Well, that's not what you were about to say.
你記得你在後車廂裡多愛講話?
- Remember how talkative you were in the trunk? - Mm-hmm.
- 阿黛兒說你一緊張就愛講話 - 她這麼說嗎?
- Adele said you do that when you're nervous. - Oh, she did, did she?
-你一直摸我的大腿 -但我沒惡意
-You kept touching me, feeling my thigh. -But in a nice way.
你拿走的西格槍有特殊意義
You know, that Sig you took from me was special.
是我爸送我的生日禮物
My dad gave it to me for my birthday.
是嗎?
Yeah?
你要把我怎麼辦?
What were you going to do with me?
我還沒想出來
l hadn't really worked that part out yet.
我只知道我喜歡你，不想……
All l knew is that l liked you, and that l didn't wanna...
離開你就再也見不到你了
leave you there on the side of the road and never see you again.
你在電梯裡招手
Then you waved to me in that elevator.
我以為你沒看到我
Yeah, l wasn't sure if you caught that.
我無法相信，我一直…
l couldn't believe it. By that time l had been...
很想你
thinking about you a lot...
而且一直想如果我們再見面
and just wondering what it would be like if we met,
如果我們能讓時間停止
if we could take a time-out.
我也這麼想
l was thinking the same thing.
如果我們能讓時間停止
l kept thinking, ''What if we took a time-out?''
如果我們能在一起一段時間
lf we... just spent some time together.
- 我在街上看到過你 - 哪裡？
- You know, l saw you on the street. - Where?
阿黛兒家外面
Outside Adele's.
- 你去看她? - 去警告她要小心奇諾
- You went to see her? - To warn her about Chino.
- 她幫了你? - 我們不該談這些
- So she did help you. - I don't think we should get into that.
對，我也不會問巴蒂的事
You're right. And l won't ask about Buddy,
或你是否見到了葛蘭
or what you guys are doing in Detroit, or if you've run into Glenn Michaels yet--
別這麼說，你讓我害怕
Okay, now, don't talk like that, because you scare me.
我們走吧
- Let's get out of here. - Yeah.
有些事情我要你知道
There's something l want you to know.
我並不是在找樂子，如果你是這麼想的話
l wasn't just looking for a fuck, if that's what you're thinking.
怎麼了?
- Or, l was-- - Why are you mad?
我不是在尋刺激，和一個搶銀行的
l was looking for some kinky thrill-- you know, score with the bank robber.
-像有些女人喜歡粗暴的…… -對
-The way some women go for rough trade-- -All right.
我不會說我幹了一個聯邦女警，你想我會嗎?
Now l can say that l fucked a U.S. marshal. Do you think l will?
我不知道
I don't know.
Mm-hmm.
過來
Come here.
我認識一個傢伙……
l know a guy...
帶了個瓶子進了銀行，說那是硝化甘油
walks into a bank with a bottle, tells everybody it's nitroglycerine.
他從櫃檯搞了些錢
He scores some cash off of the teller.
走出銀行時，瓶子掉到地上
On his way out, he drops the bottle. lt cracks on the floor.
他滑倒跌破了頭，被逮了
He slips in it. He smacks up his head. They get him.
那油只是沙拉油
The nitroglycerine was canola oil.
搶銀行的笨賊總比高明的要多
l know more fucked-up bank robbers than ones that know what they're doing.
我懷疑有幾個搶銀行的知道什麼是染色袋
l doubt one in ten could tell you where the dye pack is.
大部份搶銀行的都是蠢蛋
Most bank robbers are fucking morons.
讓你到床上找刺激的蠢蛋
For you to go to bed with one for kinky thrills,
像你說的，你也變得和他們一樣蠢
like you were saying, makes you as dumb as they are.
事實上，你不蠢
Now, you are not dumb.
你怎麼會那麼想?你怎麼認為我會那麼想?
Why would you think that? Why would you think that l would think that?
你不蠢
You're not dumb.
我不曉得
Well, I don't know about that.
你不能跌了三跤後還認為自己不笨
l mean, you can't do three falls and think you have much of a brain.
過來
Come here.
你現在對我認真了
You're getting serious on me now.
我盡量不想
Tryin' not to.
我只是想知道會發生什麼
l just want to know what's gonna happen.
你知道的
You know.
週五夜拳賽
防守。打他上面，下面
Put it together now. Put it together! Upstairs and downstairs.
- 他不想在樓下見到你 - 你醉得像婊子
- He don't want to see you downstairs! - Man, you drink like a bitch!
別下去，準備打吧
He don't want to see you-- Get your tussle on. Joe, get your tussle on!
別讓他離開那個角落
Yeah, don't let him out that corner.
別讓他出去
Don't let him out, now.
我要去小便
Hey, you know what? l gotta go take a pee.
告訴我們幹什麼?要我們替你扶老二啊
What are you tellin' us for? You want somebody to hold your pecker?
幹下去，喬
Do that work, Joe!
鼓起精神，喬
Put it together now, Joe!
對了
That's it, baby!
扁他，好極了
Take him deep! Oh, oh, my God, l love it.
把他打昏，喬 把他打昏，喬
Put him to sleep, Joe! Put him to sleep, Joe!
坐下，肯尼，對了
Sit down, Kenny. That's it! That's it!
- 想偷這部車呀 - 不要!
- You tryin' to steal this car, Glenn? - Don't, don't, don't!
我不相信
Oh, my God, I can't believe this!
又倒霉了，沒一件事情搞對
Another one of those days, huh? Nothing seems to be going right.
- 我沒有鑰匙 - 我知道
- I don't have the keys to the car. - l see that.
我不是要偷這輛車
No, l mean l am not fucking stealing the car!
- 你不是嗎? - 不是，一周前已經偷到手了
- You're not? - No, l already stole it a week ago,
在西棕櫚
whenever it was, in West Palm.
我不可能再偷一次吧
So I can't be stealing it again, can l?
- 把手放在方向盤上 - 你要…
- Put your hands on the wheel, please. - Okay, so now you're gonna...
因為偷車逮捕我?
bust me for pickin' up a car, what the--
為車，為協助犯人逃獄
For the car, for aiding and abetting a prison escape,
還為你到這裡搞的不管什麼名堂
and for conspiring to do whatever you came here for.
那些傢伙隨時都會出來找我
Listen to me. These guys, they're gonna be out here any minute looking for me,
他們是禽獸
and they're fucking animals, man.
發生什麼事，葛蘭?
What's going on, Glenn?
沒事，我只是想離開這鬼地方
Nothing. l just wanna get the fuck outta here.
我還以為這件事是你的主意
l thought this whole thing was your idea.
打劫瑞利家是我的主意
Okay, ripping off Ripley was my idea,
但這些傢伙另有搞法
but these guys, they are in a whole other level of their own.
- 瑞利，那個華爾街的傢伙? - 計劃是…
- Ripley, the Wall Street guy? - Yeah, the plan was...
明天到他辦公室接他
to pick him up at his office tomorrow...
搭他到布倫坡他家
and drive him out to his house in Bloomfield Hills.
現在，我不跟那鳥人做，你知道!
And now I don't give a shit what the guys do, you know?
- 弗理有份嗎? - 有，但他還沒出現
- And Foley was part of this. - Yeah, he's supposed to be, but he hasn't showed up yet,
- 那倒對他好 - 為什麼?
- which is good for him. - Why?
莫瑞要幹掉他……
Because Maurice is gonna kill him.
想拿賞金甚麼的
Like, try to collect the reward money or something.
但你說他還沒現身，他是打退堂鼓了嗎?
But you say he hasn't shown up yet. You think he backed out?
我不知道，他不會告訴我這些
I don't know. He doesn't exactly confide in me.
奇怪
l wonder why.
你如果想做，我們做了就離開這裡
Okay, if you're gonna do this, let's do it and get out of here.
我的屁股凍壞了
l am freezing my ass off!
你想溜，就跑吧，這樣會暖和些
lf you wanna get out of here, run. lt'll warm you up.
哦！哦！
Oh, ha, ha.
真的？
Really?
如果我發現你在騙我，我發誓……
l swear to God, Glenn, if l find out that you are lying to me, l--
我知道，你會找到我的
l know, you will find me. l believe it.
知道我在想什麼嗎?
Hey, know what l was thinkin'?
去年夏天如果你沒載我到聯邦法院
lf you didn't drive me to the federal court last summer,
你就不認識我了
you wouldn't even know who l am.
如果我不認識你，葛蘭，明天你不是坐牢就是死了
lf l didn't know you, Glenn, by tomorrow you'd be in jail or dead.
要那樣去想。現在跑吧
Think of it that way. Now run.
耶! 耶!
Yeah! Yeah!
我告訴你吧，錢在這裡
I'm tellin' you, man, the money is here.
- 史努 - 搶銀行的
- Snoop. - Hey, it's the bank robbers.
我會錯過拳賽，抓把椅子來
Y'all missin' the fights, man. Pull up a chair.
- 誰坐在那裡 - 葛蘭
- Who's sittin' here? - Oh, that's your homey, Glenn, man.
他去上廁所了……
But he bounced to the bathroom a couple minutes ago...
- 之後我們就沒見過他 - 一定是掉到茅坑裡了
- and we ain't seen him since. - Must've fell in, man.
沒錯
No doubt.
叫那兩個人去找他，他們沒找到
Yeah, sent these two looking for him. They came back shaking their heads.
如果他留下外套，又離開了一陣子……
Well, if he left his coat and he's been gone a while, then--
車還在，我查過了
- Car's here, man. l checked. - Yeah.
- 我們走了 - 走了?
- All right. We're leavin'. - Leavin'?
- 幹嘛? - 如果葛蘭跑了…
- What the fuck, Foley? - Stupid, you know where Glenn is.
- 誰在乎，他什麼也不知道 - 我以為他全知道
- Look, what you worried about Glenn for, what he know? - l thought everything.
葛蘭以為我們明天才要干
No, Glenn know everything that's supposed to happen tomorrow.
就算他跑了把我們的事告訴別人，也無關緊要
Now, he may run and tell somebody that, but that don't mean shit.
葛蘭不知道我改變了計劃
Glenn don't know l changed the plan.
今天晚上一離開這裡我們就行動
It's happenin' tonight. Soon as we leave here.
繞到我家，拿些我們需要的傢伙，就這麼干!
Go back by the house, pick up some shit we gonna need, and we just gonna do it.
- 給我幾分鐘跟巴蒂商量 - 給你兩分鐘
- Give me a minute to talk to Buddy. - You got two minutes, that's all.
- 你作決定 - 我不是要你批准
- Make up your mind, Foley. - l wasn't asking permission.
- 他們會對我們下圈套 - 我有同感
- You know they're gonna set us up. - l get that feeling, yeah.
你想我們可以在他們之前找到鑽石嗎?
You think you can get to the diamonds before they do?
跟你談個交易，你現在就離開這裡
l'll make you a deal. You get outta here right now.
我和史努一起做，再和你見面分你一半
l'll do the job with Snoop. l'll meet you anywhere you want, give you half.
-為什麼分我一半? -因你幫我逃獄
-Half for doin' what? -Gettin' me out of Glades, for starters.
誰會在背後照應你?
Who's gonna watch your back?
好了，白鬼，家庭訪間
All right, White Boy. House call.
耶, 耶, 耶
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- 準備好了? - 好了
- Ready to do this, baby? - Ready for whatever.
正點!我這一套每次都管用
Cool. My shit always work.
長生水電
Perennial Plumbing.
有人打電話給我們
Somebody in the house called.
你搞錯了，沒人在家
You don't know what you're talking about, because no one was here.
- 我們去滑雪 - 耶, 耶, 耶
- Let's go skiing. - Yeah, yeah, yeah.
你仍可以接受我的條件
You still got time to take me up on my offer.
留你和這些蠢蛋在一起?
And leave you alone with these assholes?
- 雷門庫茲 - 我是凱倫，我在瑞利家
- Raymond Cruz. - Ray, it's Karen Sisco. I'm at Ripley's house.
莫瑞米勒和另外四個人剛闖進去
l just saw Maurice Miller and four other suspects force their way into the house.
我需要後援
They're armed. I'm gonna need backup.
- 你是誰? - 我在這裡工作
- Who are you? - l work here.
我是女傭，別過來
I'm the maid. Fuck off!
我偏要這麼做，先干你，再扁你
- That's exactly what I'm gonna do: fuck you, then off you. - Hey, not yet.
- 端利在哪裡? - 他不在這裡
- Where Ripley at? - He isn't here.
- 晚上出去還是搞什麼? - 他在佛羅里達
- Out for the evening or some shit? - He's in Florida-- Palm Beach.
- 什麼時候回來? - 你們要等他啊
- When's he due back? - What difference does it make? You gonna wait for him?
瑞利先生整個季節都在那裡，從聖誕到復活節
Mr. Ripley's down for the season. Christmas to Easter.
少放屁
Stop that shit, man.
你一個人在這裡?
You're here all by yourself?
是的，只有我
That's right. Just me.
- 瑞利的保險箱和貴重品在哪? - 我不知道
- Where Ripley's safe at, keeps his valuables in? - I don't have any idea.
我諒你也不知道
l fuckin' bet you don't.
我們要上樓到他的臥室找一找
We gonna take a look upstairs in the man's bedroom, all right?
你和巴蒂找樓下的房間
You and Mr. Buddy look at all the rooms down here.
檢查那些畫，以及牆後
Check the paintings, behind the walls.
他一定有保險箱，在這附近
Check the fuckin' walls in the closets. The man's got a safe. It's here somewhere.
會不會在他佛羅里達的家裡?
What about his place down in Florida?
如果你先查明，我們在佛羅里達時，就先查那些牆了
lf you called, we could have checked the walls down there before we left.
我是說如果你願找到他的話
That is, if you'd bothered to find out where he was. You follow me?
把這婊子帶上樓
Man, take this bitch upstairs.
上樓
Upstairs!
你如果想按警鈴，或甚麼的話
Listen, you try and trip any alarms, anything like that,
你就死定了，明白嗎?
you gonna be a dead Hazel, you understand me?
- 我們在哪裡?保險箱在哪裡? - 那裡
- Hey, hey, where we at? Where is it? - Over there.
- 穿過這個嗎? - 我不滑雪
- Ever wear one of these? - I don't ski.
看好那個女傭，我要到處看看
Keep an eye on the maid. l'll have a look around.
坐下來
Go sit down. Please.
媽的，這痞子過這種生活
Damn, Mo. How's this motherfucker livin', man? Shit!
檢查牆上畫的後面
Check behind the pictures on the walls, man.
喂，找到一些套子
Hey, Mo. Found some rubbers.
白波，你為什麼在床墊下找?
White Boy, why the fuck you lookin' under the mattress?
那傢伙不會把鑽石藏在那兒的
You know dude ain't gonna hide no diamonds under there.
媽的，這個痞子
Damn! Dumb 'bama motherfucker.
- 弗理在哪裡? - 照你說的，在檢查別的房間
- Where Foley at, man? - He's checkin' the other rooms like you said, boss.
盯好他
Man, keep a eye on Foley.
肯，別動那收音機，放張CD
Ken, stop fuckin' with the radio. Put on a CD.
- 這些樂隊我一個都不認識 - 隨便找一個
- I don't recognize none of these bands, Mo. - Just pick somebody.
什麼，「如何唱的像麥克波頓」
What, ''How To Sing Like Michael Bolton''?
你想聽什麼?
What the fuck you wanna listen to, huh?
- 我喜歡舒伯特 - 舒伯特，我不喜歡
- l like Schubert. - Schubert? Well, I don't.
弗理!
Uh, Foley?
酷
Cool.
911占線啊，理查
911 got you on hold, Richard?
- 弗理! - 還好嗎？
- Foley! - How you doin'?
到底發生什麼事?
What in God's name is happening here?
- 誰在樓上? - 史努比米勒，幾個他的朋友
- Who's upstairs? - Snoopy Miller, couple of his friends.
莫瑞，蘭坡監獄的那個?
- Maurice, from Lompoc? - Yup.
他們把美姬抓住了嗎
Have they got Midge up there?
有哪個男人那麼晚讓女人應門?
What kind of a man lets a woman answer the door this time of night?
我們以為那是她丈夫來這裡查看她
We thought it was her husband. He comes here and checks up on her.
我應該在佛羅里達的
I'm supposed to be down in Florida.
待會兒你就會巴不得自己是在佛羅里達了
ln a few minutes, you're gonna wish you were. Let's go, come on.
坐下，看魚吧
Why don't you sit down? We'll have a look at your fish.
這個行，這個行
Oh, that's workin'. That's workin'.
幹你娘，我找到保險箱了
Motherfucker! l found the safe, yo!
哪兒都別去
Don't go nowhere.
- 媽的，我們要慶祝一下 - 瞧那婊子
- Oh, shit! We gonna have a party! - Look at that bitch.
找到保險箱了
They found the safe.
- 干 - 巴蒂，你記得理查嗎?
- Fuck. - Buddy, you remember Richard, don't you?
- 嘿，房子不錯 - 謝謝
- Yeah, hi. Nice house. - Thank you.
我們可以敲這個把手
Yeah, man. We just all hit this handle,
把這炸開
blow this sucker wide open, man.
準備一下
Uh-huh. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Let's get ready.
你想用這玩意兒幹掉我
Oh, Dude-- you're gonna kill me with that.
- 你去哪兒了? - 找到一些牛排
- Where you been, man? - Found some steaks.
- 牛排 - 好大一塊
- Steaks? - Yeah, some big ones, bro.
來吧，把這保險箱炸開
Man, come on. Blast this damn safe open, man.
- 他在那兒找吃的 - 蠢蛋
- He's down there lookin' for food. - Fool.
拿好，不對，到一邊去
All right. Hold it. No. Get to the side, man. All right.
數到三， 一、二、三
On three. One, two, three.
- 老天，他們在對美姬開槍 - 坐下，迪克
- Jesus Christ, they're shooting Midge! - Sit down, Dick.
他們在打開保險箱，不是你的女傭
They're trying to open up the safe, not your maid.
媽的
Oh, shit.
連個破洞也沒有
Man, we didn't even crack this sum' bitch.
打那門鉸鏈
- Okay, hit the hinges. - Uh-huh.
摀住你的耳朵，這聲音會很響
Put your finger in your ear, man. This is gonna be loud.
數到三，一、二……
All right, on three. One, two--
暗碼是3-10-44
The combination is 3-10-44.
- 理查的生日 - 多謝
- Richard's birthday. - Thank you.
他們掛了?
Are they dead?
我們得找弗理
We gotta find Foley, man.
真不敢相信事過境遷你還生我氣
Can't believe you're still angry with me after all this time.
我沒生你的氣，老實說，我真看開了
I'm not angry with you, Richard. ln fact, I'm completely relaxed.
我真搞不懂，是魚讓我冷靜下來
The thing is, I can't figure if it's the fish that are cooling me out,
還是水箱底下那些未切割的鑽石
or all those uncut diamonds in the bottom of the tank, there.
該死
Goddamn.
葛蘭說得沒錯，那大概值五百萬吧?
Dumb-fuck Glenn was right. You got about 5 million worth in there?
五百二十萬
Five point two.
看起來就像不起眼的石頭
They just look like plain ol' rocks!
對，你想抓一把嗎?
They sure do. You wanna grab 'em, Buddy?
如果換了我是你，我拔腿就溜了
lf l were you, l'd get up and run.
- 我不能留下美姬 - 他們會殺了你
- I'm not leaving Midge. - Don't be an asshole. They're gonna kill you.
那我就認命了，我不離開她，我愛上她了
Well, if that's my fate then so be it, but I'm not leaving her. I'm in love with her.
- 算了，傑克 - 祝你好運，理查
- Come on, Jack. - Good luck, Richard.
- 快點，傑克 - 他們要強暴那個女傭，是嗎
- Come on, Jack. - Shit. They're gonna rape that maid, aren't they?
看樣子是
By the look of those guys, they'll rip her too.
- 然後再把他們幹掉 - 大概是吧
- Then they're gonna kill 'em. - At least.
Rip, Rip.
- 狗娘養的 - 那些是我的衣服嗎
- Tricky motherfucker. - Are those my suits?
是我的，看看你
Naw. These are my suits. Look at you, man.
你都躲在哪兒了?
Where you been hidin', Dick?
我們成了
We made it, didn't we?
- 先上車 - 我要回去
- All you gotta do is get in the van, baby. - I'm goin' back in.
- 我和你一起去 - 在機場和我碰頭
- I'm goin' with you. - No, you dump the van, meet me at the airport.
- 我開瑞利的車來 - 傑克--
- l'll get one of Ripley's cars. - Jack--
你和你老姊大概會在電話裡聊這事聊上一個月
The shit that's about to go down here, you'll be on the phone with your sister for a month.
- 我們現在扯平了 - 這兒
- All I'm sayin' is we're square. - Here.
耶
Yep.
傑克
Jack.
滾開
Get outta here.
- 把這玩意拿下來 - 滾開
- Get that shit off. - Get your hands off me!
閉嘴!沒人會來救你
Fuck you, shut up! Nobody's gonna help you.
美姬，珠寶究竟在哪裡?
- Midge! - Fuck Midge, man. Where the jewels at, Dick?
- 弗理拿去了 - 弗理在哪裡?
- Foley-- Foley's got them. Go after Foley! - Where the fuck is Foley, man?
美姬!
Midge?
- 美姬! - 給我坐下
- Midge! - Sit your punk ass down, man.
豬玀
- Ooh, goddamn! - Son of a bitch!
你走前門，我走後門
Man, take the front stairs. I'm gonna take the back.
- 你沒事吧? - 理查在哪裡
- You all right? - Where's Richard?
在樓下，在這兒等著
He's downstairs. You wait here.
不許動，把槍丟下
Hold it, asshole. Drop the gun.
丟下
Drop it!
把槍放下
Put the damn gun down, now.
馬上
Now!
放下
Put it down!
在那兒待著別動，莫瑞
Stay right there. Don't move. Maurice!
我找到弗理了
l got Foley!
莫瑞
Maurice!
沒有多的彈夾可給我用的?
Ain't got another clip l can use, do you?
沒有
No, I don't.
- 從沒開過槍吧? - 對，最近才學會
- You ain't never shot a gun before, have you? - Not until recently, no.
- 有點緊張 - 一點點
- You a little nervous? - Little bit, yeah.
在這種情況下，很可能
You know, a situation like this has a high potentiality...
被這些狗娘養的給逃了
for the common motherfucker to bitch out.
所以我想，為什麼要冒險?
So l figure, why take a chance?
婊子
Bitch!
干你娘
- Aw, sh--! - Motherfucker!
住手，舉起手來
Stop! Put your hands in the air!
傑克?
Jack?
- 我知道你在上面 - 呸
- l know you're up there. - Shit!
- 肯尼在哪裡 - 他在上面
- Where's Kenneth? - He's up here.
他掛了
He's dead.
- 算了，傑克，別這樣 - 就當不是我
- Come on, Jack, don't. - Pretend it's not me.
- 你以為我會對你開槍? - 你不開，別人也會開
- You think l'd shoot you? - lf you don't, somebody else will.
你現在算什麼?亡命之徒?
What're you now? A desperado?
- 把槍放下 - 我不回去坐牢
- Put the gun down. - I'm not goin' back.
不要逼我，把槍放下
Jack, please, don't make me do this. Put the gun down.
渾蛋，傑克，把槍放下
Damn it, Jack, put the gun down!
沒有時間了
No more time-outs.
算你贏，傑克
You win, Jack.
- 我沒法射你 - 你開了，你射中我
- I can't shoot you. - You did. You shot me.
你知道我的
You know what l mean.
抱歉，我真希望事情不這樣
I'm sorry. l wish things were different.
機場
Airport.
他們還沒確定是否要控他殺人罪
Yeah, they don't know yet if they want to bring him up on the homicides.
我想不會，他們會把他在關一陣子
l doubt if they will. They'll just put a detainer on him.
等審完以後，他會回佛羅里達
When they're through with him here, he'll go back to Florida.
你會把他押解回來嗎?
Are you gonna go get him?
可能，幹嘛
It's possible. Why?
想想而已
Well, you know, l was just thinkin'.
你可以一路上和他逍遙
You can have a nice time with him on the ride down,
續上你們之間的那段插曲
picking up where your interlude or whatever you call it left off,
然後把他扔回監獄
and then you can throw him in the shithouse.
他知道自己在做什麼
He knew what he was doing.
沒人逼他搶銀行
Nobody forced him to rob banks.
我可憐的女兒，真堅強
My little girl-- the tough babe.
我稍後再和你連絡
l'll call you later.
再見
Good-bye.
傑克
Jack.
給你一個禮物
l got you a present.
路上用的
Something for the road.
不過，旅途結束後我還是要收回的
I'm gonna have to take it away, though, soon as the ride is over.
傑克弗理?來見海極亨利
Jack Foley? Meet Hijirah Henry.
這個名字很特別
What kind of a name is Hijirah?
- 是回教名字 - 代表什麼?
- It's lslamic. - What's it stand for?
「海極」是西元622年墨罕默得逃離麥加意思
The ''Hijirah'' was Mohammed's flight from Mecca in 622.
- 他的逃離? - 利文沃的兄弟給我取的名字
- His flight? - Brothers in Leavenworth gave me that name.
你在和利文沃待過?
You were in Leavenworth, huh?
- 待過一段日子 - 什麼意思?
- For a time. - Meaning?
- 時間到我就走了 - 你逃跑了
- Meaning, time came, l left. - You busted out.
是從自己不願待的地方離開
l prefer to think of it as an exodus from an undesirable place.
- 過多久你又被逮到? - 那一次嗎?
- How long before they caught up with you? - That time?
- 還有多少次啊? - 那是第九次
- There were others? - Yeah. That was the ninth.
第九次?
The ninth?
如果把那次從監獄醫院逃走也算的話，就是第十次
Well, ten if you count that prison hospital in Ohio l walked away from.
- 亨利，你倒蹺頭不少次 - 海極
- You done a lot of walkin', Henry. - Hijirah.
我們現在出發去葛雷茲
Hijirah. Now we're off to Glades.
好像是吧
Yeah, it looks that way.
我昨天晚上本來應該跟一個女警官走的
l was supposed to leave last night with the lady marshal,
不知為什麼她要等
but for some reason she wanted to wait.
- 是嗎? - 我想兩人坐車省點錢吧
- She did, huh? - Guess it's cheaper taking two of us down in one van.
可能，說不定她以為我們有很多可聊的
Could be. Maybe she thought we had a lot to talk about.
是嗎?聊什麼?
Really? Like what?
我不知道，到佛羅里達有好一段路要走
I don't know. Long ride to Florida.
It's your thing Do what you wanna do
I can't tell ya who to sock it to
lf you want me to love you maybe l will
Believe me, woman it ain't no big deal
Ah, you need love now just the same as l do
Makes me no difference now who you give your thing to
Ah, it's your thing Do what you wanna do
I can't tell ya who to sock it to
It's your thing Do what you wanna do now
Ahhhh, stay
All right
Lord, have mercy
Ahhhh, it's your thing Do what you wanna do
Ooh, I can't tell ya who to sock it to
Hit me, man, it's your thing Do what you wanna do
I can't tell ya who to sock it to
I'm not tryin' to run your life
l know you wanna do what's right
Oh, give your love, girl to whomever you choose
How can you lose with the stuff you use
It's your thing Do what you wanna do
I can't tell ya who to sock it to
It's your thing, yeah Do what you wanna do
Don't let me tell ya who to sock it to
Let me hear ya say It's my thing
- It's your thing - l do what l wanna do
I can't tell ya